<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<galaw><metadata><coretitle>Acts of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</coretitle><creator>Georgia</creator><subject>Law, Georgia</subject><description>Georgia. Acts and resolutions of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</description><publisher>ATLANTA: FOOTE  DAVIES CO.</publisher><contributors><contributor /></contributors><date>19231107</date><type /><format /><identifier /><source /><language>English</language><relation /><coverage /><rights /></metadata>
<document initial.page="1" type="INFERRED">
<page id="GA1923.2.P1" no="GA1923.2.1" type="INFERRED" />

<titlepage><title>ACTS AND RESOLUTIONS<br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER">GENERAL ASSEMBLY<br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER">STATE OF GEORGIA<br set="CENTER">AT ITS<br set="CENTER">EXTRORDINARY SESSION<br set="CENTER">November 7 to December 14, 1923<br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></title><sessiondate>19231107</sessiondate><sessiondate>19231214</sessiondate><pubinfo><p>COMPILED AND PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY OF THE STATE</p><p>1923</p><p>FOOTE  DAVIES CO., STATE PRINTERS</p><p>ATLANTA, GA.</p></pubinfo></titlepage>

<page id="GA1923.2.P2" no="GA1923.2.3" type="INFERRED" />

<toc><title><b>TABLE OF TITLES</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><tocdiv><parttitle>PART I.PUBLIC LAWS.</parttitle></tocdiv><tocdiv><parttitle>PART II.RESOLUTIONS.</parttitle></tocdiv></toc>

<page id="GA1923.2.P3" no="GA1923.2.5" type="INFERRED" />

<body><part><preface><p>STATUTES OF GEORGIA PASSED BY THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY AT THE EXTRAORDINARY SESSION November 7 to December 14, 1923</p></preface><title>PART I.PUBLIC LAWS<br set="CENTER" /></title>

<page id="GA1923.2.P4" no="GA1923.2.7" type="INFERRED" />

<contentslist><title>ACTS.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p>Department of Audits and Accounts Created.</p><p>Department of Revenue Created.</p><p>State Text-Book Commission Created.</p><p>General Tax Act.</p><p>Certain Industries Exempt from Taxation for Five Years.</p><p>Cigars and Cigarettes, Tax on Dealers in; Act Amended.</p></contentslist><law id="L1923V2N001" initial.page="7" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle>DEPARTMENT OF AUDITS AND ACCOUNTS CREATED.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 1.</lawnbr><fulltitle>An Act to create and establish the Department of Audits and Accounts; for the appointment, term of office and removal of a State Auditor; for the salary to be paid to and the bond to be given by the State Auditor; to provide for the appointment and compensation of examiners and clerical assistants for the State Auditor; to define the powers and duties of the State Auditor; to provide for an examination and audit of all books, records, accounts, vouchers, warrants, bills and all other records or each and every department, institution, commission, bureau, agency and officer of the State of Georgia, to require such departments, etc., to comply with the rules and regulations promulgated by the State Auditor and to produce their books, records, etc., for examination; to provide for quarters for and necessary equipment, supplies, etc., for the Department of Audits and Accounts; to require the State Auditor to make specific

<page id="GA1923.2.P5" no="GA1923.2.8" />

recommendations to the next General Assembly; to repeal conflicting law, and for other purposes.</fulltitle><p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the State of Georgia, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same, That the Department of Audits and Accounts is hereby created and established; that the head of said department shall be an experienced auditor and accountant, who shall be appointed by the Governor and whose appointment shall be confirmed by the Senate, and who shall serve for a term of four years and until his successor is appointed and qualified, and who shall be known and designated as State Auditor. That the State Auditor may be removed from office by the Governor on account of inefficiency or malpractice, but only after being heard with respect to such charges. <sidenote>Department of Audits and Accounts created.</sidenote> <sidenote>State Auditor; appointment, qualification and term of office.</sidenote> <sidenote>Removal for inefficiency, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the State Auditor shall be paid a salary of four thousand ($4,000.00) dollars per annum, payable monthly, and shall also be paid his actual travelling expenses while actually engaged in the performance of his official duties, to be proven by his sworn itemized statement and approved by the Governor. The State Auditor shall devote his entire time to the performance of the duties of his office, and shall give bond, to be filed with and approved by the Comptroller-General, in the sum of ten thousand ($10,000.00) dollars, payable to the Governor and his successors in office, conditioned that he shall truly and faithfully perform the duties of his office and shall account for all public funds coming into his hands or under his control, the premium on which bond shall be paid by the State. <sidenote>Salary and travelling expenses of State Auditor.</sidenote> <sidenote>Must devote entire time to duties of office.</sidenote> <sidenote>Amount and condition of bond to be given by State Auditor.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the State Auditor shall be authorized, and he is hereby authorized and empowered, with the approval of the Governor to appoint and employ the following officers and assistants, each of whom shall hold office during the pleasure of the State Auditor, to wit: <sidenote>Authority of appointment in State Auditor.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P6" no="GA1923.2.9" />

<p><list><item><p>(a) One chief examiner, at a salary of not to exceed twenty-four hundred ($2400.00) dollars per annum. <sidenote>Chief examiner; salary.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(b) One assistant examiner, at a salary not to exceed twenty-four hundred ($2400.00) dollars per annum. <sidenote>Assistant examiner; salary.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(c) Such clerks or stenographers as in the opinion of the State Auditor might be necessary, but at an aggregate expense or salary of not to exceed fifteen hundred ($1500.00) dollars per annum. <sidenote>Clerks and stenographers; expense.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(d) The chief examiner and assistant examiner shall also be paid their actual travelling expenses while actually engaged in the performance of their official duties, to be proven by their sworn itemized statement and approved by the Governor. <sidenote>Travelling expenses of chief examiner and assistant examiner.</sidenote></p></item></list></p><p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the duties and powers of the State Auditor shall be as follows: <sidenote>Duties and powers of State Auditor.</sidenote></p><p><list><item><p>(a) To devise, and, with the approval of the Governor, to promulgate, install, and establish forms and records for the collecting and paying out of all monies, funds and revenues of the State and to insure the protection and proper use of all stores, equipment and property of the State. <sidenote>To devise forms and establish correct methods of record.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(b) To thoroughly examine all financial transactions of all the State departments, institutions, agencies, commissions, bureaus and officers and to keep such accounting records as are necessary to provide and maintain a current check upon the fiscal affairs and transactions of all State departments, institutions, agencies, etc. <sidenote>To examine all financial transactions of, and maintain a current check upon all State departments, etc.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(c) To examine and thoroughly audit, at least once a year, and more frequently if possible, each and all of the books, records, accounts, vouchers, warrants, bills and all other papers and records of each and every department, institution, agency, commission, bureau and officer of the State of Georgia which or who receives funds from the

<page id="GA1923.2.P7" no="GA1923.2.10" />

State or which is maintained in whole or in part by public funds or fees or commissions; and upon the completion of each such audit the State Auditor shall prepare a complete report of the same in triplicate, one copy of which he shall file with the official in charge of the department, institution, etc., so examined, one copy of which he shall transmit to the Governor, and the third copy shall be filed in the office of the State Auditor as a permanent record and for the use of the press of the State; and in which report the State Auditor shall call special attention to any illegal, improper or unnecessary expenditures, all failures to keep records and vouchers required by the law, and all inaccuracies, irregularities and shortages, and shall make specific recommendations for the future avoidance of the same. <sidenote>All accounts of each State department, audited annually at least.</sidenote> <sidenote>Reports in triplicate and with whom filed.</sidenote> <sidenote>What reports must contain.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(d) To prepare annual and, whenever required, special reports to the Governor and the General Assembly, showing the general financial operation and management of each State department, institution, agency, commission and bureau, and whether or not the same is being handled in an efficient and economical manner, and calling special attention to any excessive cost of operation or maintenance, any excessive expense, and any excessive price paid for goods, supplies or labor by any such department, institution, agency, etc. <sidenote>Annual and special reports to Governor and General Assembly; what must contain.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(e) To make special examination into and report of the place and manner in which the funds of the State are kept by the several departments, institutions, agencies, commissions, bureaus, and officers after the same have been drawn from the State Treasury or after the same have been collected and report who has possession of the same or where the same are deposited, and whether the same draw interest, the rate of interest, and whether the same are properly protected by bond. <sidenote>Special examination and reports on State depositories, funds, etc.</sidenote></p></item></list></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P8" no="GA1923.2.11" />

<p>Provided, this Act shall not be construed to authorize the State Auditor to remove or in any way interfere with any funds so deposited. <sidenote>Proviso as to authority not conferred.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That either the Governor, The State Investigating and Budget Commission, the Appropriations Committee of the House of Representatives or the Appropriations Committee of the Senate, shall have the right and authority to direct and require the State Auditor to make a special examination into and audit of all of the books, records, accounts, vouchers, warrants, bills, and other papers and records, and the financial transaction and management of any department, institution, agency, commission, bureau and officer of the State of Georgia at any time. <sidenote>Special examinations and audits; who may require.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That said State Auditor shall, upon the request of either the Governor or the Comptroller-General, make an examination into and report upon the necessary books, records and accounts of those persons, firms and corporations required by law to pay an occupation tax as distributors of motor fuels, as defined in the Act approved August 10, 1921, (Acts 1921, pages 83 to 85) and the Act or Acts amendatory thereof, and also of those persons, firms and corporations required by law to pay a tax upon the retail sales price of cigarettes and cigars, as defined in the Act approved August 14, 1923; said examination to be made at such time as might be fixed by the Comptroller-General and for the purpose and to the extent of ascertaining whether or not said tax is paid and collected as provided by law. <sidenote>Accounts of certain tax-payers audited.</sidenote> <sidenote>Distributors of motor fuels.</sidenote> <sidenote>Dealers in cigarettes and cigars.</sidenote> <sidenote>When audit made.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That all officers, agents, employees, departments, institutions, commissions and bureaus of the State are directed and required to conform to and comply with all rules, regulations and forms devised, promulgated and installed by the State Auditor in conformity with this Act,

<page id="GA1923.2.P9" no="GA1923.2.12" />

and shall produce and turn over to the State Auditor or his assistants, for examination and audit, whenever demanded by said State Auditor, all of their books, records, accounts, vouchers, warrants, bills and other papers dealing with or reflecting upon the financial transactions and management of such department, institution, agency, commission, bureau, or officer, including any and all cash on hand, but not including cash in bank, the amount of cash in bank to be ascertained by certificate furnished the State Auditor by the bank. <sidenote>Compliance with rules of State Auditor and production of books and secords for examination and audit required of all State departments, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the State Auditor shall co-operate with and shall furnish all information requested by the State Investigating and Budget Commission and the Appropriations Committees of the General Assembly. <sidenote>Co-operation required of State Auditor.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the provisions of this Act shall in no way affect the duties of the bookkeeper and accountant as defined and provided for in Section 65 of the Act codifying the school laws of the State of Georgia, approved August 19th, 1919, nor with rights, powers and duties of the State banking department. <sidenote>Certain school and banking laws not affected.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the department of audits and accounts shall be provided with suitable apartments at the State Capitol, furnished at the State's expense, as may appear proper and necessary by the Governor, and said department shall be furnished from time to time, upon approval of the Governor, necessary equipment, furniture, fuel, light and other proper conveniences for the transaction of said department, the expense of which shall be paid by the State in the same manner as the expenses of other offices at the Capitol are paid. <sidenote>Quarters of department; expense, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the State Auditor shall thoroughly investigate the different systems and methods now practiced by the

<page id="GA1923.2.P10" no="GA1923.2.13" />

several departments, institutions, agencies, commissions, bureaus, etc., in the handling of their financial affairs and in the purchasing of supplies and materials, and he shall recommend to the 1924 session of the General Assembly: <sidenote>Investigations and recommendations by the State Auditor.</sidenote></p><p><list><item><p>(a) A system of financial accounting and management under which all bills and items of expense of each department, institution, agency, commission, bureau, and officer of the State can be investigated, audited and approved before the same are paid; and <sidenote>Auditing of all accounts.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(b) The practicability of establishing a central purchasing agent or agency to purchase the general or staple supplies and materials for the several State departments, institutions, agencies, etc. <sidenote>Central purchasing agent.</sidenote></p></item></list></p><p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this Act shall be and the same are hereby repealed. <sidenote>Conflicting laws repealed.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 6, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1923V2N002" initial.page="13"><shorttitle>DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE CREATED.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 2.</lawnbr><fulltitle>An Act to create a Department of Revenue for the State of Georgia; to provide for the appointment of a Commissioner of Revenue; to fix his term of office, compensation and bond, and to prescribe his duties; to provide for the necessary office force; to provide for the appointment of six deputy commissioners, to prescribe their duties and fix their compensation and bond; to prescribe what taxes shall come under the jurisdiction of the revenue department; to provide a penalty against delinquent tax payers, and to provide relief from said penalty; to provide for the prosecution of parties who refuse to pay delinquent taxes upon demand; to require tax collectors of the State to co-operate with the department of revenue,

<page id="GA1923.2.P11" no="GA1923.2.14" />

and to issue executions upon request of the commissioner or his deputies; and for other purposes.</fulltitle><p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the State of Georgia and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same, That there shall be a Department of Revenue for the State of Georgia, and the executive or administrative officer of said department shall be known as commissioner of revenue; he shall be appointed by the Governor for a term of six years, and qualify by giving bond as herein prescribed. He shall have his office in the Capitol and be furnished with necessary clerical help and office supplies. Provided, said commissioner of revenue may be removed by the Governor at any time for inefficiency, incompetency, or failure to faithfully discharge the duties of the office; Provided, further, the commissioner of revenue may discharge any deputy for inefficiency or failure to faithfully discharge the duties of such deputy. <sidenote>Department of Revenue created.</sidenote> <sidenote>Commissioner of revenue; appointment, qualification and term of office.</sidenote> <sidenote>Quarters and clerical help.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to removal for inefficiency, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Commissioner may discharge deputies.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That said commissioner of revenue shall have authority to appoint not-more than six deputies, no two of whom shall be appointed from the same congressional district or section of the State, whose duties shall be to look after the collection of delinquent taxes of every kind that may be due the State of Georgia, particularly to investigate and collect delinquent license taxes, special or occupation taxes, automobile tag taxes, chauffeurs' license taxes, gasoline sales taxes, and stamp taxes on cigars and cigarettes; it shall be the further duty of such deputies to check up estates subject to inheritance taxes and to report information with reference to said estates to such officers as may be charged with the administration of the inheritance tax laws of this State. All delinquent taxpayers shall be subject to a penalty of twenty per cent. for non-payment of said taxes. All special or occupation taxes shall be deemed delinquent after thirty days from the expiration of the quarter in which they are payable. None of the

<page id="GA1923.2.P12" no="GA1923.2.15" />

provisions of this Act shall apply to ad valorem taxes or those required by law to be returned to the tax receiver and entered in the tax digest. <sidenote>Authority of commissioner of revenue as to appointment of deputies; and duties of deputies.</sidenote> <sidenote>Delinquent taxpayers; penalty.</sidenote> <sidenote>Delinquent after thirty days.</sidenote> <sidenote>Ad valorem taxes, etc., not affected.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That it shall be the duty of the tax collectors of this State to co-operate with the department of revenue in supplying information as to delinquents, and said department shall have access to all records of tax collectors of this State in putting into effect the operation of this Act, and that said tax collectors shall not be entitled to any commission whatever in the collection of delinquent taxes except where such collections are made directly by such tax collector, and then such commission shall not exceed that of ten per cent. now provided by law, and said tax collectors shall not then have right to relieve any delinquent of penalty provided in this Act, but shall collect said penalty and remit same, less his commission of ten per cent. to said revenue department. <sidenote>Duty of tax collectors as to co-operation with department of revenue in cases of delinquency.</sidenote> <sidenote>As to commission; amount and when not paid.</sidenote> <sidenote>Right of relief to cease.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the commissioner of revenue shall receive as compensation a salary of four thousand dollars per annum, together with his travelling expenses when travelling on business of the State in connection with his department. The clerical help in his office shall receive such compensation as may be approved by the Governor; the deputies employed by said department of revenue shall each be paid salaries not to exceed two hundred dollars per month, in addition to their necessary expenses incurred while travelling in the discharge of the duties required of them, such expenses to be paid only upon a sworn itemized statement for such expenses made by said deputy and approved by the commissioner of revenue. <sidenote>Salary and travelling expenses of commissioner of revenue.</sidenote> <sidenote>Compensation of clerical help, salaries of deputies, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That before entering upon the duties of their respective offices the commissioner of revenue shall furnish bond to the Governor in such sum as the Governor may

<page id="GA1923.2.P13" no="GA1923.2.16" />

require, not to exceed twenty thousand dollars, and each deputy shall likewise give bond conditioned for the faithful accounting for all moneys collected by him with security approved by the Governor, in a sum of not less than five thousand dollars, premiums on said bonds to be paid by the State. <sidenote>Amount and condition of bond to be given by commissioner of revenue and each deputy commissioner.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That said deputy commissioners shall report to the commissioner of revenue at least every week in detail as to amount collected by each and the source from which the same has been collected, and pay over to the commissioner of revenue the amount shown in said report to have been collected; and it shall be the duty of the commissioner of revenue to report all such collections to the Treasurer of the State once each week, and to pay into the State Treasury at such times all amounts that have been paid over to him by his deputies, except automobile tag taxes and chauffeurs' license taxes, which shall be paid to the Secretary of State. The failure on the part of said commissioner to so account for the funds paid to him by the deputies, or the failure on the part of any deputy to promptly report and pay over to the commissioner any moneys collected by him, shall be a breach of their respective bonds, and in the discretion of the Governor, terminate the term of said commissioner or deputy. <sidenote>Reports and payments to be made by commissioner of revenue and deputy commissioner.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty for failure to report and pay.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 7. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That in addition to the duties already prescribed for the commissioner of revenue in this bill, he shall discharge such duties as may, from time to time, be required of him by law. <sidenote>Additional duties of commissioner of revenue.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 8. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That said commissioner shall be required to take and subscribe before the Governor an oath to faithfully and impartially discharge the duties of his office, which oath shall be in addition to the oath required of all civil officers. <sidenote>Oath of commissioner of revenue.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P14" no="GA1923.2.17" />

<p>Sec. 9. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the salary of the commissioner of revenue shall be provided for in the general appropriations bill, and a fund for the payment of salaries of deputies and clerks, as well as the expenses of the office and field forces, shall be provided in the general appropriations bill. The commissioner of revenue shall make requisition on the Governor, accompanied by detailed statement covering salaries and expenses for each month, and the Governor, upon approval of such requisition, shall issue his warrant upon said fund for the amount so approved; provided, that until this can be done at the next regular session of the legislature, the compensation and expenses of the commissioner, and of the office force and the field force, shall be payable out of the twenty-five per cent. penalty imposed upon delinquent taxpayers by Section 2 of this Act, and should the penalties amount to more than the salaries and expenses of the department, the amount in excess thereof shall be paid into the State Treasury at the end of each quarter. <sidenote>How salaries and expenses of department of revenue shall be paid and manner of payment.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 10. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That it shall be the duty of the commissioner of revenue to direct prosecutions instituted against any person or corporation subject to payment of any special taxes who may refuse to pay said taxes upon demand of a deputy, and to require the tax collector in the county of the residence of such delinquent taxpayer to issue execution for the amount of the taxes shown to be due. <sidenote>Duty of commissioner of revenue to prosecute delinquents and require tax collectors to issue executions.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 11. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That after the passage of this Act, and the same is in operation, should any individual, who is delinquent in any of the taxes heretofore prescribed, voluntarily remit the amount of delinquency to the office of the department, within thirty days, he may be relieved of the penalty prescribed. This, however, not to be effective beyond thirty days from date that office of department is in actual operation. <sidenote>Relief of delinquents; time limit.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P15" no="GA1923.2.18" />

<p>Sec. 12. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the department of revenue shall be required to keep accurate accounts of all collections and expenditures, and shall submit a detailed report of same up to June the first of each year to the General Assembly of Georgia, at its regular sessions. <sidenote>Annual reports of collections and expenditures to General Assembly.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 13. Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid, That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this Act be and the same are hereby repealed. <sidenote>Conflicting laws repealed.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 14, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1923V2N003" initial.page="18"><shorttitle>STATE TEXT-BOOK COMMISSION CREATED.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 3.</lawnbr><fulltitle>An Act to provide a method by which school books may be furnished free, or rented, to the children of Georgia under a local option plan, by counties, cities, local school systems and separate school districts; to provide a time and method by which school books shall be adopted; to provide a method of distribution at definite prices; to repeal conflicting laws; to provide for exchange price of all books, and for other purposes.</fulltitle><p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the General Assembly of Georgia, That within sixty days after the passage of this Act it shall be the duty of the State Board of Education, acting as the State Text-Book Commission, to adopt a series of school books for the schools of the State according to the laws now governing the adoption of school books; Provided, that the said text-book commission shall not be limited or restrained by, or restricted to the fifty per cent. exchange rate for old books as provided in the Act of 1903, known as the State Uniformity Act, but the said State Text-Book Commission is hereby authorized and directed to obtain the best exchange rate for old books possible, Provided, That the exchange rate or allowance for the old books shall

<page id="GA1923.2.P16" no="GA1923.2.19" />

be as much as is allowed by the publisher of the new book as the rate allowed in any other State under like conditions and terms of adoption; Provided, the change of books made under this Act shall not exceed fifty per cent. of the entire list for an adoption period. <sidenote>Duty of State Board of Education to act as State Text-Book Commission in adoption of school books and the establishment of exchange rates.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to amount of exchange rate.</sidenote> <sidenote>Change of books limited.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all the terms, conditions and benefits obtainable and applicable, in the State Uniformity Act of 1903, and also of the Act of 1916, approved August 8th, known as the Yeomans' Act, shall apply to and be available for all the schools of this State governed by the adoption made under this Act, <sidenote>State Uniformity Act of 1903 and Act of 1916 applicable.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That for the purpose of furnishing free school books, either by renting, lending or giving them to the children of the State, any county, city, separate districts, or independent school districts may have the right to use a part of this school fund derived from State appropriation, local taxation, gifts or bequests, according to the wish of the local school authorities. If a county as a whole wishes to rent, lend, or give free books, the question may be determined by the Board of Education of the county. If a local or separate district wishes to so furnish books the question may be determined by the Board of Trustees of such district, but must be approved by the County Board of Education. If the books are rented to the children, the rental price shall in no event be greater than fifty per cent. of the price of the book. <sidenote>Local option as to free school books.</sidenote> <sidenote>County Board of Education to determine or approve.</sidenote> <sidenote>Rental price limited.</sidenote></p><p>For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section, it shall be the duty of the State School Board, through the State Superintendent of Education, to devise plans, methods, rules and regulations governing the same. <sidenote>Regulation by State School Board.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted, That school boards of any division handling school funds, are authorized to furnish books free to children whose parents or guardians, in the judgment of the school board, are unable to provide their children with books. <sidenote>Indigents furnished books free.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P17" no="GA1923.2.20" />

<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted, That County Boards of Education shall be required to have on hand a sufficient supply of books for the various schools under their charge and shall give public notice five days prior to the opening of such school session that such books are available, and the County Boards of Education may designate some agent or agents to handle such books for the various schools under their jurisdiction. <sidenote>Duties of County Boards of Education as to supply of books and public notice.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 6. Be it further enacted, That all laws in conflict with Act are hereby repealed. <sidenote>Conflicting laws repealed.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 19, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1923V2N004" initial.page="20"><shorttitle>GENERAL TAX ACT.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 4.</lawnbr><fulltitle>An Act to annually, in addition to the ad valorem tax on real and personal property as now required by law, to levy and collect a tax for the support of the State government and public institutions; for educational purposes in instructing children in the elementary branches of an English education only; to pay the interest on the public debt; to pay maimed and indigent Confederate soldiers, and widows of Confederate soldiers, such amounts as are allowed them by law; to pay the public debt when due; to prescribe what persons, corporations, professions, business, and property are liable to taxation; to prescribe the methods of collecting and of receiving certain of said taxes; to prescribe questions to be propounded to tax-payers, and to provide penalties for violations thereof; and to repeal conflicting laws, and for other purposes.</fulltitle><p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the State of Georgia, That the terms and provisions of this Act shall not take effect and become operative until January 1, 1924, and shall continue thereafter. <sidenote>Act effective Jan. 1, 1924.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P18" no="GA1923.2.21" />

<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That in addition to the ad valorem tax on real estate and personal property, as required by the Constitution and now provided for by law, the following specific and occupation taxes shall be levied and collected each year after the passage of this Act, beginning in 1924. In all cases in this Act where population controls the amounts of tax or license fee to be paid, the last census report of the Federal Government shall govern. <sidenote>Specific and occupation taxes.</sidenote> <sidenote>When U. S. census governs.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 1. Upon each and every inhabitant of the State between the ages of twenty-one and sixty years, on the day fixed for the return of property for taxation, a poll tax of one ($1.00) dollar, which shall be for educational purposes, in instructing children in the elementary branches of an English education only. Provided, this shall not be demanded of blind persons, nor crippled, maimed or disabled Confederate veterans relieved of such taxes under and by authority of Section 766, Volume 1, of the Code of 1895, nor shall this tax be required or demanded of female inhabitants of the State who do not register for voting. <sidenote>Poll tax.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to exemptions.</sidenote></p><p>(a) Provided further, That those female inhabitants who have heretofore registered may avail themselves of the benefits of this Act and be relieved of said tax, by applying to the tax collector of their county, and have their names stricken from said registration book; and it shall be the duty of said tax collector to issue to such females who may apply to have their names so stricken a certificate, which certificate shall bear date when issued and shall give the name of such females, and state in substance that said named female has been stricken from the registration book, and is no longer a registered voter for that year. <sidenote>Relief of registered female voters.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 2. That the Governor, by and with the assistance of the Comptroller-General, is authorized and empowered annually to levy and assess a tax on the ad valorem value of the taxable property of this State such rate as may be sufficient to raise a net amount of $100,000 as a sinking

<page id="GA1923.2.P19" no="GA1923.2.22" />

fund to pay off and retire the valid outstanding bonds of the State as they fall due, as required by Article 7, Section 14, Paragraph 1, of the Constitution. The tax above authorized shall be specially levied and collected and separate accounts of the same shall be kept by the Treasurer, and the money arising therefrom shall be applied to paying off the valid bonds of the State as they mature. The said amount so received each year shall be applied to paying off and retiring the valid bonds of the State maturing in their order continuously. All bonds retired under the provisions of this Act shall be cancelled and stamped with the words sinking funds, by the Treasurer and filed in his office. <sidenote>Ad valorem tax for sinking fund for State bonds.</sidenote> <sidenote>Separate accounts by State Treasurer.</sidenote> <sidenote>Cancellation of bonds.</sidenote></p><p>In addition to the foregoing levy, the Governor, by and with the assistance of the Comptroller-General, shall also levy and assess such additional rate of tax on the taxable property of this State as may be necessary to meet the appropriations of the General Assembly of Georgia for each succeeding year. The aggregate ad valorem tax levy in any one year not to exceed the tax rate limit fixed by the Constitution of this State. The Comptroller-General and State Tax Commissioner shall cause returns of public service and utility corporations whose returns are made to the Comptroller-General, to be equalized with the returns of real estate taxpayers of Georgia, in order that the percentage of actual values returned by such corporations shall be as great as the percentage of actual values returned by land owners of Georgia. <sidenote>Additional ad valorem tax to meet appropriations of General Assembly for each year.</sidenote> <sidenote>Tax rate limit.</sidenote> <sidenote>Equalization of tax values.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 3. Professions. Upon each and every practitioner of law, medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, chiropodist, dentistry, and upon each and every veterinary surgeon, optician, optometrist, masseur, public accountant, or embalmer, and upon every civil, mechanical, hydraulic, or electrical engineer, or architect, charging for their services as such, $15.00, and the validity of their licenses is made contingent upon the payment of the tax herein provided. And no municipal corporation or county authority shall levy or

<page id="GA1923.2.P20" no="GA1923.2.23" />

collect an additional tax on the professions, business or occupations enumerated above, which shall be returned to the tax receiver of the county of his residence by any person engaged therein on the first day of January, and entered by the receiver on the digest of the county. <sidenote>Professional taxes.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 4. Officials. Upon the president of each express, telegraph, telephone, railroad, street railroad, steamboat or navigation company, electric light, gas company, water company, sleeping car company, palace car company, building and loan association, and investment and loan company, doing business in this State, $25.00. <sidenote>Certain corporation presidents.</sidenote></p><p>Provided, said tax shall not apply to local building and loan associations fostered as a civic undertaking and not conducted for financial gain or profit. <sidenote>Proviso as to exemptions.</sidenote></p><p>In case the president of any of the companies enumerated in the preceding paragraph does not reside in this State, then in each case the general agent, superintendent, or other person or official in charge of the business of such companies, residing in this State, shall be required to pay the tax of $25.00 hereby imposed, and no municipal corporation, or county authorities shall levy or collect an additional tax on the officials enumerated above, either as a license, tax or fee. The president or other officials herein named, of the companies enumerated above, are required to make a return as such to the tax receiver of the county of his residence, as of January 1st, which return shall be entered on the digest by said receiver. <sidenote>Presidents non-resident, other officials to act.</sidenote> <sidenote>Duty as to returns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 5. Abstract Companies. Upon each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of making abstract of title to property in cities of 20,000 inhabitants or over, $100.00; in cities between 10,000 and 20,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in cities and towns of less than 10,000 inhabitants, $25.00. Provided, This tax shall not be required of attorneys at law who have paid the professional tax required of them by Paragraph 3, Section 2, of this Act. <sidenote>Title abstract companies; certain cities and towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to attorneys at law.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P21" no="GA1923.2.24" />

<p>Paragraph 6. Advertising. Upon each person, firm or corporation conducting the business of an advertising agency using other means than billboards, $50.00; upon each person, firm or corporation conducting the business of advertising by signs painted, pasted or printed on billboards or other places where space is leased, rented or sold, in each county where located, fifty cents for each location, and a location is defined to be 75 lineal feet or fractional part thereof; and Provided further, That before painting or posting such locations or fractional part thereof, it shall be the duty of the person or persons so advertising to register with the ordinary and tax collector of said county as required by law, and in case of any increase of advertising the ordinary shall in each instance be notified as to the number of locations. <sidenote>Advertising agents.</sidenote> <sidenote>Location defined.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to registry, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 7. Bill Distributors. Upon all bill distributors and parties engaged in the business for profit in towns or cities, $25.00. <sidenote>Bill distributors.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 8. Agencies, Collecting, Commercial and Mercantile. Upon each person, firm or corporation engaged in business as a collecting, commercial, mercantile, or any other agency of like character, $200.00 in every county in the State where they have an office or branch office. <sidenote>Collecting; commercial and mercantile agencies.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 9. Agencies, Detective. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating a detective agency, or doing detective work for hire or compensation, for each office established in this State in or near cities or towns of 25,000 or more inhabitants, $200.00; in or near cities or towns from 10,000 to 25,000 inhabitants, $50.00; and in or near cities or towns of less than 10,000 inhabitants, $25.00. <sidenote>Detective agencies; certain cities or towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 10. Agencies, Teachers. Upon each person, firm or corporation conducting a teachers' agency or bureau, $25.00 in each county where it has an office. <sidenote>Teachers' agencies.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 11. Amusement Parks. Upon each person, firm or corporation running, leasing or operating an amusement

<page id="GA1923.2.P22" no="GA1923.2.25" />

park, other than baseball, football or bicycle parks, hereinafter mentioned, where two or more amusement devices, resorts, or attractions are operated, and an admission fee is charged for any one or more of the exhibits, resorts or attractions, $250.00. Provided, This paragraph shall not be construed to exempt or relieve any individual device, resort, amusement or attraction located in said park from paying any specific or license tax herein imposed. <sidenote>Amusement parks.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to construction.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 12. Athletic Clubs. Upon every athletic club, and upon every association or person giving boxing or sparring or wrestling exhibitions where an admission of 50 cents to $1.00 is charged, $50.00 for each exhibition; where admission charged is $1.00 to $1.50, $100.00; and where the admission charged is $1.50 and over, $200.00 for each exhibition. <sidenote>Athletic clubs, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 13. Auctioneers. Upon each and every auctioneer selling jewelry by auction in this State, $200.00 in each county in which he conducts said business. <sidenote>Auctioneers, jewelry.</sidenote></p><p><list><item><p>(a) Upon each and every auctioneer selling junk by auction in this State, the sum of $100.00 in each county in which he conducts said business. <sidenote>Junk.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(b) Upon each and every auctioneer selling furniture and household goods by auction in this State, the sum of $100.00 in each county in which he conducts said business. <sidenote>Furniture and household goods.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(c) Upon each and every auctioneer selling live stock, farm implements and produce by auction in this State, the sum of $25.00 in each county in which he conducts said business. Provided, This shall not apply to co-operative selling or to producers of live stock from selling same. <sidenote>Live stock.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to co-operative selling, etc.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(d) Upon each and every non-residential real estate auctioneer, the sum of $100.00 in each county in which he conducts said sale. Each and every resident real estate auctioneer shall pay the sum of $50.00 in each county in which he conducts said sale. At the time he registers with the ordinary of the county, before paying the tax, every

<page id="GA1923.2.P23" no="GA1923.2.26" />

auctioneer must specify the kind and style of sale he intends to conduct. <sidenote>Real estate; non-residential.</sidenote> <sidenote>Real estate; residential.</sidenote> <sidenote>Registry regulations.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(e) Provided, This Section and the subsections thereto shall not apply to sheriff and the parties acting as auctioneers for executors, administrators, guardians and commissioners conducting sales by virtue of the order of any court of this State. <sidenote>Proviso as to sales by sheriffs. executors, etc.</sidenote></p></item></list></p><p>Paragraph 14. Automobiles. Upon every agent of, upon every dealer in, and upon every person soliciting orders for retail sale of automobile, not including wholesale dealers or distributors soliciting or canvassing for local dealers, the sum set out below, viz.: In each county with a population of less than 20,000, $25.00; in each county with a population of between 20,000 and 30,000, $55.00; in each county with a population of between 30,000 and 50,000, $85.00; in each county with a population between 50,000 and 75,000, $110.00; in each county with a population between 75,000 and 100,000, $165.00; in each county with a population between 100,000 and 150,000, $220.00; in each county with a population exceeding 150,000, $275.00. Provided, however, That nothing in this Act shall conflict with the provisions fixing a license upon exclusive dealers in used cars. Such dealer, agent or solicitor selling or offering for sale automobiles at retail shall be required to pay one license fee only in each county, so as to provide that all persons soliciting orders, or selling automobiles at retail shall pay a license to become a dealer or agent, and such license shall entitle such dealer to sell any make or makes of new or second-hand automobiles, and shall entitle said dealers to operate in connection with said business a service station, in the said county in which said license is paid; any dealer having paid such tax to be allowed any number of employees for the purpose of selling cars within the county wherein such tax has been paid. <sidenote>Automobile dealers; certain counties.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 15. Used Cars. Upon every person, firm or corporation dealing exclusively in used automobiles or

<page id="GA1923.2.P24" no="GA1923.2.27" />

trucks, or second-hand automobiles or trucks, the following sums, viz.: In each county with a population of less than 20,000, $25.00; in each county with a population over 20,000 and not over 50,000, $50.00; in each county with a population exceeding 50,000, $100.00. <sidenote>Used cars, automobiles, trucks; exclusive dealers in; certain counties.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 16. Automobile Tires or Accessories. Upon every wholesale dealer in automobile tires or automobile accessories of any kind whatsoever, the sum of $100.00 for each place of business, and upon every retail dealer the sum of $10.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Automobile tires or accessories, wholesale and retail.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 17. Automobile Schools. Upon all automobile schools, $10.00 in each county. <sidenote>Automobile schools.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 18. Automobile Assembling Plants. Upon every agent or representative of any foreign or non-resident corporation said agent or representative having an office in this State, operating an automobile assembling plant, $300.00 in each county. <sidenote>Automobile assembling plants.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 19. Automobile Truck Assembling Plants. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating an automobile truck assembling plant, $300.00 in each county. <sidenote>Automobile truck assembling plants.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 20. Automobile Garages. Upon each person, firm or corporation carrying on the business of operating garages, either for storage or repairing automobiles, in cities of more than 35,000 inhabitants, $75.00; in the cities between 20,000 and 35,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in cities between 10,000 and 20,000 inhabitants, $25.00; in cities and towns of 1,000 to 10,000 inhabitants, $15.00; in cities and towns of less than 1,000 inhabitants, $5.00; and persons operating such garages within one mile of the limits of all incorporated cities, $5.00. <sidenote>Automobile garages; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 21. Cars Operated for Hire. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating or keeping automobiles for hire, whether in connection with a garage or not, a tax according to the following scale, whether in or outside of the corporate limits of any city or town, viz.: For

<page id="GA1923.2.P25" no="GA1923.2.28" />

each automobile so operated in or near towns or cities of population not over 1,000, $5.00; of population from 1,000 to 5,000, $10.00; of population from 5,000 to 15,000, $15.00; of population from 15,000 to 30,000, $20.00; of population from 30,000 to 50,000, $25.00; of population of 50,000 and over, $40.00. Provided, however, These taxes shall not be required of operators or keepers of automobiles for hire when such automobiles are used over or operated upon a fixed or uniformed route, and such cases the schedule of fees shall be as follows: Upon every person, firm or corporation operating automobiles for transportation of passengers upon a regular fixed route, commonly known as jitneys, and for a uniform fare of not more than 10 cents, the following amounts: For a five-passenger car or less, $15.00 per annum, and for every car carrying more than five passengers, $25.00 per annum. <sidenote>Automobiles for hire; certain cities and towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to fixed routes; jitneys, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 21-A. Motor Busses. Upon every person, firm or corporation operating a motor bus for the transportation of passengers upon a regular fixed route between cities or towns, $25.00 for each bus. Provided, That no municipal corporation or county authority shall levy or collect an additional occupation tax on persons, firms or corporations operating motor busses. Every such person, firm or corporation is required to register with the ordinary and pay the tax herein provided to the tax collector of the county of his residence. <sidenote>Motor busses.</sidenote> <sidenote>No additional occupation tax.</sidenote> <sidenote>Registry and payment.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 22. Awning or Tent Makers. Upon all awning or tent makers, $15.00 in each county. <sidenote>Awning and tent making.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 23. Barbers' Schools. Upon every barber school, $15.00 in each county. <sidenote>Barbers' schools.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 24. Barber Shops. Upon every barber shop the sum of $5.00 for each chair in use except that in cities and town of less than 5,000 the amount shall be $2.50 for each chair in use. <sidenote>Barber shops.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P26" no="GA1923.2.29" />

<p>Paragraph 25. Barber Supplies. Upon all agents for barber supplies, $50.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Barber supplies.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 26. Baths. Upon all persons, firms or corporations operating all Turkish baths, Russian or vapor baths, $50.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Bath, Turkish, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 27. Ball and Racing Parks. Upon each person, firm or corporation owning, leasing or operating any park, or place where baseball, football, or other similar game is played, or where automobile, motorcycle, horse or bicycle races or contests are held, and where admission fees are charged, in the cities of more than 50,000 inhabitants, or within five miles thereof, $200.00; in cities with over 20,000 and not over 50,000, or within five miles thereof, $100.00; in cities with over 10,000 and not over 20,000, or within five miles thereof, $50.00; in cities and towns of less than 10,000, or within five miles thereof, $20.00. Provided, That this tax shall apply only to those parks and places wherein professional games are played or professional contests are held. <sidenote>Ball and racing parks; certain cities and towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to professional games or contests.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 28. Bagatelle, Billiard, Jenny Lind, Pool or Tivoli Tables. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating for public use and charging for the use thereof, any billiard, bagatelle, Jenny Lind, pool or tivoli table in cities of 100,000 inhabitants or more, $100.00; in cities of not less than 50,000 and not more than 100,000 inhabitants, $75.00; in cities of not less than 25,000 and not more than 50,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in cities of not less than 10,000 and not more than 25,000 inhabitants, $30.00; in cities or towns of less than 10,000 inhabitants, $20.00. <sidenote>Bagatelle, billiard, pool, etc.; tables operated for public use; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 28-A. Upon each person, firm or corporation who keeps or holds for hire or for sale, for himself or as agent for resident or non-resident owner, any bagatelle, billiard, Jenny Lind, pool or tivoli table or other table of like character, for each place of business in this State, $100.00.</p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P27" no="GA1923.2.30" />

<p>Paragraph 29. Bond Makers. Upon each person, firm, or corporation engaged in the business of procuring or signing bonds, or depositing collateral in lieu of bonds for compensation (except duly licensed bonding companies, and duly authorized officers of this State who are required to give bond to qualify as such officers), $50.00 in each county. <sidenote>Bagatelle, billiard, pool, etc.; tables for sale or hire.</sidenote> <sidenote>Bond making or deposit of collateral for compensation.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 30. Book Agents. Upon each agent or canvasser for books, maps, or lithographic prints, in each county in which he shall do business, $5.00. Provided, This shall not apply to bona fide students earning their way through school or college, or persons selling Bibles. <sidenote>Book agents.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 31. Brokers, Stocks and Bonds. Upon each person, firm or corporation dealing in bonds or stocks, either exclusively or in connection with other business, the sum of $100.00 for each town or city in which such persons, firms or corporations maintain an office. <sidenote>Stock and bond brokers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 32. Brokers, Merchandise and Commission Merchants. Every person, firm or corporation doing business in this State, and who receives or distributes provisions or merchandise, including flour, hay, grain, coal, coke, lumber, brick, or any other article of merchandise shipped to such person, firm or corporation, for distribution on account of the shippers, or who participates in the profits ensuing from or occurring out of sales of such provisions or merchandise as above described, or who invoices such sales, or who collects money therefor, shall be deemed a broker. Every person, firm or corporation buying or selling for another any kind of merchandise on commission, shall be deemed a commission merchant. Every person, firm or corporation shall pay for the privilege of transacting the business of a commission merchant or broker in merchandise, in cities of 40,000 or more inhabitants, $50.00; in cities of less than 40,000 inhabitants, $25.00. <sidenote>Merchandise brokers and commission merchants.</sidenote> <sidenote>Brokers defined.</sidenote> <sidenote>Commission merchant defined.</sidenote> <sidenote>Certain cities.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 33. Brokers, Printing. Upon all brokers, agents or agencies for printing, bookbinding, or lithographing,

<page id="GA1923.2.P28" no="GA1923.2.31" />

$25.00 in each county in which such broker or agent has an office or place of business. <sidenote>Printing brokers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 34. Brokers, Real Estate. Upon each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of buying or selling real estate on commission, or as agents, renting real estate, in cities of 50,000 or more, $50.00; in cities of 25,000 to 50,000 inhabitants, $30.00; in cities from 10,000 to 25,000 inhabitants, $20.00, and in cities or towns of less than 10,000 inhabitants, $15.00. And if such person shall engage in auctioneering or selling property at public outcry or by auction sales, he shall also be liable for and required to pay the tax required of real estate auctioneers by Paragraph 13 of this Section, to wit: $50.00 in each county. <sidenote>Real estate brokers; certain cities and towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Liabilities.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 35. Brokers, Railroad and Theatre Tickets. Upon each railroad and theatre ticket broker or scalper, when not prohibited by law, operating in cities of more than 10,000 inhabitants, $100.00; in cities or towns of less than 10,000 inhabitants, $50.00. <sidenote>Railroad and theatre ticket brokers; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 36. Burglar Alarm and Automatic Sprinkler. Upon all burglar alarm companies, and upon all automatic sprinkler companies, or agents therefor, the sum of $25.00 for each agency or place of business in each county. Upon each dealer in fire engines and apparatus or either of them, $100.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Burglar alarm, automatic sprinkler and fire apparatus.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 37. Cards, Dealers in. Upon each dealer in playing cards, $10.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Playing cards.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 38. Card Writing Stands. Upon all card writing, cutting or engraving stands, $5.00 for each stand in each county. <sidenote>Card writing stands.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 39. Carpet Cleaners. Upon all carpet and rug cleaning companies not connected with laundries, $10.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Carpet and rug cleaning.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 40. Cemetery Companies. Upon all cemetery companies, agencies, offices, etc., $50.00 in each county.</p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P29" no="GA1923.2.32" />

<p>Paragraph 41. Circuses. Upon each circus company or other company or companies giving such exhibition beneath or within a canvas inclosure, advertised in print or parade in any manner whatsoever, as a circus, menagerie, hippodrome, spectacle or show implying a circus, in or near cities of 40,000 or more inhabitants, for each day it may exhibit, $500.00; in or near cities between 20,000 and 40,000 inhabitants, for each day it may exhibit, $300.00; in or near cities between 5,000 and 20,000 inhabitants, for each day that it may exhibit, $250.00; in or near cities or towns of less than 5,000 inhabitants, for each day it may exhibit, $100.00; in or near cities or towns of less than 1,000 inhabitants, for each day it may exhibit in the State of Georgia, $100.00. <sidenote>Cemetery companies.</sidenote> <sidenote>Circuses; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 42. Side Shows. Upon each side show accompanying a circus company in or near cities of 5,000 population or more, $50.00; and in or near all cities or towns of less than 5,000 population, $25.00. <sidenote>Side shows; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 43. Clipping Bureaus. Upon each clipping bureau, $10.00. <sidenote>Clipping bureaus.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 44. Coal, Coke, or Wood. Upon each person, firm or corporation dealing in coal, coke, and wood, or coal and coke, whether for themselves or as agents or as brokers, in cities of more than 1,000 inhabitants, and not more than 10,000, $10.00; in cities of more than 10,000 and not more than 20,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in cities of more than 20,000, $100,000. Provided, That dealers in wood only shall pay a tax of $10.00. Said tax payable for each place of business. <sidenote>Coal, coke and wood; certain cities and towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to dealers in wood only.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 45. Concerts, Shows and Exhibitions. Upon all concerts, shows and exhibitions charging an admission, not otherwise herein taxed, in or near cities of less than 5,000 inhabitants, $25.00; in or near cities of more than 5,000 and not more than 20,000, $50.00; in or near cities of more than 20,000 and not more than 50,000, $75.00; in or near

<page id="GA1923.2.P30" no="GA1923.2.33" />

cities of more than 50,000, $100.00 for each day. Provided, This section shall not apply to exhibitions given by local performers nor to exhibitions the entire proceeds of which are for charitable, benevolent purposes, nor to entertainments commonly known as Chautauquas. Provided further, That this section shall not apply to histrionic, dramatic and operatic performances given in regularly licensed theatres and opera houses, but upon each such theatre or opera house in towns of less than 2,000 inhabitants, $2.50 per month; in cities from 2,000 to 5,000 inhabitants, $4.00 per month; in cities from 5,000 to 10,000 inhabitants, $7.00 per month; in cities from 10,000 to 25,000 inhabitants, $10.00 per month; in cities of over 25,000 inhabitants, $12.50 per month. <sidenote>Concerts, shows and exhibitions; certain cities.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to charitable entertainments, chautauquas, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to regularly licensed theatres and opera houses.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 46. Construction Companies. Upon each person, firm or corporation accepting a contract to construct bridges, dams, waterworks, roads, railroads, street paving, cantonments, or other stuctures or works of a like public nature, in each county where doing business, one-tenth of one per cent of the contract price, then one-tenth of one per cent upon cost of such work, and Provided, That the aggregate tax paid by any one contractor or firm or corporation under this section shall not exceed the sum of $500.00 in any one county in any calender year. <sidenote>Construction companies.</sidenote> <sidenote>Maximum tax.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 47. Contractors. Any person, firm or corporation accepting orders or contracts for doing any work on or in any building, or structure, requiring the use of paint, stone, brick, mortar, wood cement, structural iron and steel, sheet iron, galvanized iron, metallic piping, tin, lead, electric wiring or other metal, or any other building, or who shall accept contracts to do any paving or curbing on sidewalks or streets, public or private property, using asphalt, brick, stone, cement, wood or any composition, or who shall accept an order for, or contract to excavate earth, rock or other material, for foundation or any other purpose, or who shall accept an order or contract to construct

<page id="GA1923.2.P31" no="GA1923.2.34" />

any sewer of stone, brick, terra cotta or other material, shall be deemed to be a contractor. Every contractor shall, on the first day of January in each year, procure from the ordinary in the county in which he has his office a license to carry on the business of a contractor. Provided, That if such contractor has no office in this State then he may procure such license from the ordinary of the county where he conducts his business. Every such contractor shall pay for the privilege of transacting business in this state, $10.00, provided the amount of all orders or contracts accepted do not exceed $10,000, and $1.00 additional for each $1,000.00 of orders or contracts accepted above $10,000; this to be paid as follows: $10.00 to be paid at the beginning of the year or at the commencement of business within any year, and thereafter returns to be made at the end of the quarter to the tax collector, showing the amount of orders or contracts accepted during the quarter and the amount of tax due upon the orders or contracts above $10,000 to be paid at the end of each quarter with the making of this report. Provided, The provisions of this section shall not apply in cases where the contract price does not exceed the sum of $500.00, and where the contractor does not employ more than two assistants. <sidenote>Contractors, Contractor defined.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to license, amount of tax and time of payment.</sidenote> <sidenote>When contract price is less than $500.00.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 48. Corporations, Domestic. All corporations incorporated under the laws of Georgia shall, except those that are not organized for pecuniary gain or profit, and those that neither charge nor contemplate charging the public for services rendered, in addition to all other taxes now required of them by law, are hereby required to pay each year annual license or occupation tax as specified in the following scale: <sidenote>Domestic corporations.</sidenote></p><p><list><item><p>Corporations with capital not exceeding $10,000, $10.00. <sidenote>Amount of taxes to be paid.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $10,000, and not over $25,000, $15.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $25,000, and not over $50,000, $20.00.</p></item>

<page id="GA1923.2.P32" no="GA1923.2.35" />

<item><p>Corporations with capital over $50,000, and not over $75,000, $30.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $75,000, and not over $100,000, $50.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $100,000, and not over $300,000, $100.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $300,000, and not over $500,000, $200.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $500,000, and not over $1,000,000, $300.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $1,000,000, and not over $2,000,000, $500.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $2,000,000, and not over $3,000,000, $600.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $3,000,000, and not over $4,000,000, $700.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $4,000,000, and not over $5,000,000, $800.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $5,000,000 and not over $6,000,000, $900.00.</p></item><item><p>Corporations with capital over $6,000,000, $1,000.00.</p></item></list></p><p>Tax required by this paragraph to be paid to the tax collector of the county where such corporation has its home office of business, and the payment of this tax will relieve such corporations from the payment of said tax in any other county in which it does business, and to that end the tax collector shall furnish such duplicate receipts as may be needed for authorized agents of the corporation in other counties of this State. <sidenote>Where paid and duty of tax collector as to receipts.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 49. Corporation, Foreign. Upon every agent or representative of any foreign or non-resident corporation, said agent or representative having a place of business or office in this State, in addition to all other taxes

<page id="GA1923.2.P33" no="GA1923.2.36" />

now required of them by law, shall be, and they are hereby, required to pay each year an annual license or occupation tax fixed in accordance with the capital stock of the corporation represented by them, as specified in the preceding paragraph of this section (wherein is fixed the license or occupation tax required of corporations chartered under the laws of Georgia), per schedule or scale therein set forth. Provided, That if such foreign or non-resident corporations shall pay to the Comptroller-General of this State the amount of the occupation or license tax prescribed as per said schedule for resident corporations, then the agents of such foreign or non-resident corporations shall be relieved from said occupation tax. And to this end said foreign corporations shall register their name, capital stock, and the names of their agents with the Comptroller-General at the beginning of each year, and upon said license or occupation tax being paid, it shall be the duty of the Comptroller-General to furnish said corporation a certificate or duplicate receipt for each agent that said tax has been paid, and the presentation of such certificate or duplicate receipt by such agent to the tax collector of his county shall be sufficient evidence of such payment and authorize the agent to be relieved of said tax. The payment of this tax shall not be construed so as to relieve the corporation or agent of any other license or occupation tax whatever. Provided, That this and paragraph 48 of this section shall not apply to insurance companies, or to sewing machine companies, or to companies doing or operating a real estate loan business as mentioned and described in Paragraph 70 hereinafter, which are separately taxed by other provisions of this Act. Provided, further, That all returns by corporations, resident or non-resident, must be made under oath, and when any corporation paying this license or occupation tax requires or demands more than two duplicate certificates for agents, then such corporation shall be required to pay an additional fee of $1.00 for each duplicate certificate or receipt over and above the first two mentioned.</p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P34" no="GA1923.2.37" />

<p>Paragraph 50. Dance Halls. Upon each person or persons operating public dance halls where dancing is permitted or taught for hire, $100.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Foreign corporations.</sidenote> <sidenote>Occupation tax required of each agent, and amount of same.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to relief of agents by foreign corporation making proper registration and payment.</sidenote> <sidenote>Duty of Comptroller-General as to certificate and duplicate receipts.</sidenote> <sidenote>Certain excepted corporations.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to returns under oath, and payment of certain fees.</sidenote> <sidenote>Dance halls; public.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 51. Devices, Bowling and Ten-Pin Alleys, Cane Racks, Shooting Galleries, etc. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating for gain a bowling, box-ball, ten-pin alley or alley of like character, shooting galleries, or booth where firearms are used for firing at a target, and upon persons operating for gain any table, stand, machine or place for performance of games not prohibited by law, and any rack or booth or place for pitching or throwing rings at canes, knives, or other things of value, or any table or stand for rolling balls for play or for sale or disposition of prizes, for each stand, table, alley, gallery, machine, rack, booth or other place put in use at each place of business in this State, the sum of $50.00. <sidenote>Bowling alleys, amusement devices, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 52. Skating Rinks. Upon the owner, manager, keeper or lessee of any skating rink in this State, where any fee or charge is made for admission, for the use of skates, or skating, in counties having a population of more than 100,000 inhabitants, the sum of $100.00; in counties of 50,000 and not over 100,000, the sum of $50.00; in counties of less than 50,000 population, the sum of $25.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Skating rinks; certain counties.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 53. Directories. Upon each person, firm or corporation compiling a city directory or directories of any character, and selling or supplying the subscription, the sum of $125.00. The above tax shall not be construed to apply to telephone companies issuing directories for use in the telephone exchanges. <sidenote>Directories.</sidenote> <sidenote>Exception.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 54. Dog and Pony Shows. Upon each dog, pony or horse show, where the entire show is exclusively an exhibition of trained dogs, ponies, or horses and monkeys, or a combination of any of them, beneath a tent, canvas or enclosure, where an admission fee of fifteen cents or

<page id="GA1923.2.P35" no="GA1923.2.38" />

more is charged, the sum of $50.00 for each day it may exhibit, and upon such shows with an admission fee of less than fifteen cents, the sum of $30.00 for each day it may exhibit in this State. <sidenote>Dog and pony shows.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 55. Dry Cleaning. Upon all persons, firms or corporations engaged in dry cleaning, $25.00 for each place of business. Provided, this Paragraph shall not apply to laundries paying the tax imposed by Paragraph 72 of this Act, nor to pressing clubs paying the tax imposed by Paragraph 55-A of this Act. <sidenote>Dry cleaning.</sidenote> <sidenote>Exceptions.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 55-A. Pressing Clubs. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating a pressing club, $5.00. <sidenote>Dressing clubs.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 56. Electrical Agents. Upon all electrical contractors, $10.00 for each county. <sidenote>Electrical contractors.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 57. Emigrant Agents. Upon each emigrant agent, and upon each employee of such agents, doing business in this State, $1,000.00 for each county in which such agents or employee may do or offer to do business. Provided, That no emigrant agent or employee shall take from this State or attempt to take from this State any person until after first giving a bond to be accepted and approved by the Commissioners of Commerce and Labor, conditioned to pay any valid debt owing by said person to any citizen of this State. <sidenote>Emigrant agents.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to giving certain bonds.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 58. Employment Agencies. Upon all employment agencies or bureaus doing business in this State, $50.00 for each county. <sidenote>Employment agencies.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 59. Travelling Horse Traders or Gypsies. Upon each company of travelling horse traders, or travelling gypsies, or travelling companies or other transients, travelling persons or firms, engaged in trading or selling merchandise or live stock of any kind, or clairvoyant, or persons engaged in fortune telling or palmistry, $250.00, to be collected by the tax collector in each county and distributed

<page id="GA1923.2.P36" no="GA1923.2.39" />

as follows: To the county where collected, $125.00; to the State, $125.00, which tax shall be collected in each county where they carry on either kind of business herein mentioned. This tax shall apply to any person, firm or corporation who themselves, or by their agents, travel through the State carrying live stock and carrying with them cooking utensils and live in tents, or travel in covered wagons, and who may be a resident of some county or who reside without the State, and who are commonly called travelling horse traders and gypsies, and such persons or corporation shall be liable to pay this tax. Such tax shall constitute a lien on any live stock owned by such travelling persons or firms. Provided, That no Confederate soldier, indigent, or any other person, firm or corporation shall be exempted from the tax provided under this section. Provided, further, that this tax shall not be required of bonafide residents of this State who have paid the tax required in Paragraph 69. <sidenote>Travelling horse traders or gypsies.</sidenote> <sidenote>Lien on live stock.</sidenote> <sidenote>Who not exempt.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to non-requirement.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 60. Gasoline or Oil Trucks. Upon each person, firm or corporation selling oil or gasoline from a wagon or truck, $10.00 for each wagon or truck in each county. <sidenote>Gasoline, oil trucks.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 61. Insurance Agents. Upon each local insurance agent doing business in this State, and upon each and every solicitor or sub-agent for any resident or non-resident company doing business in this State, $10.00 for each county in which they shall transact or solicit insurance business. Provided, This shall not apply to the agents of mutual fire associations or companies operating solely on mutual obligations. <sidenote>Insurance agencies.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to exceptions.</sidenote></p><p><list><item><p>(b) Upon each and every traveling or special or general agent, or manager of any life, fire, accident, casualty, liability, fidelity or surety insurance company conducting the business of such companies in this State, $100.00, payable in the county of the residence of the agent, and the

<page id="GA1923.2.P37" no="GA1923.2.40" />

tax collector's receipt shall be his authority to go into any other county without the payment of an additional tax. <sidenote>Life, fire, accident, casualty, liability, fidelity or surety insurance.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(c) Upon each and every traveling or special or general agent, or manager or superintendent of any assessment life insurance company or such benefit or accident insurance company or live stock insurance company doing business in this State, whether for a resident or non-resident company, $50.00, payable in the county of the residence of the agent, as provided above for other insurance companies. <sidenote>Assessment life, benefit or accident, or live stock insurance.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(d) Upon all adjustment bureaus employing adjusters a tax of $50.00 for each person who adjusts any loss, said tax payable in the county where the bureau is located, and the receipt of the tax collector for the payment of said tax shall authorize the person named in the receipt to go into any county in the State. <sidenote>Adjustment bureaus.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(e) Upon each and every person who adjusts insurance losses, not connected with an adjustment bureau, $50.00, payable in the county of his residence and the receipt of the tax collector shall be his authority to do business in any part of the State. Provided, That this tax shall not apply to local insurance agents who adjust losses without remuneration. <sidenote>Independent insurance adjusters.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to local insurance agents.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(f) The license taxes imposed by this paragraph must be paid in advance by said agent or agents to the tax collector of the county of his residence before said agents shall be authorized to act as agents for any such company. Provided, That the railroad ticket agents selling accident tickets shall not be deemed insurance agents in the sense of this paragraph. <sidenote>Payment must must be in advance.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to definition.</sidenote></p></item></list></p><p>Paragraph 62. Ice Cream Dealers. Upon each person, firm or corporation manufacturing ice cream or selling same at wholesale in or near cities of more than 50,000 inhabitants, $100.00; in or near cities from 20,000 to 50,000 inhabitants, $75.00; in or near cities of from 10,000 to 20,000,

<page id="GA1923.2.P38" no="GA1923.2.41" />

$50.00; and in or near cities of less than 10,000 inhabitants, $10.00. <sidenote>Ice cream dealers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 63. Non-Resident Bottlers. Upon each non-resident person, firm or corporation delivering for sale by truck or trucks any carbonated beverages in this State, $150.00. <sidenote>Non-resident bottlers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 64. Itinerant Practitioners. Upon every itinerant doctor, dentist, optician, optometrist, veterinary surgeon, osteopath, chiropractor, or specialist of any kind, doing business in this State, $25.00 for each county in which they may practice or do business. Provided, that if any one of said itinerant specialists shall peddle or sell any drug, medicine, remedy, appliance, spectacles, glasses or other goods, in connection with the practice of his profession, he or they shall be subject to the tax required of peddlers or travelling vendors of patent proprietary medicine, nostrums, etc., by Paragraph 88 of this Act, to wit: $50.00 in each county where they may offer to sell such articles. Provided further, That the provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to persons whose fixed place of business is in any county of this State, and who have paid the professional tax required by Paragraph 3 of the Act. <sidenote>Itinerant practitioners.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to peddlers or travelling vendors, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to application of this tax.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 65. Junk Dealers. Upon each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of dealing in junk in or near cities of over 50,000 inhabitants, $100.00; in or near cities of from 10,000 to 50,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in or near cities of from 3,000 to 10,000 inhabitants, $25.00; in cities or towns under 3,000, or within ten miles thereof, $10.00; each junk dealer, his clerk, agent or employee, shall keep a book, open to inspection, in which he shall make entries of all railroad iron, brass, pieces of machinery, plumbing materials, unused farm implements, automobile parts, fixtures or accessories, purchased by him, together with the name of the party from whom purchased, and upon failure to keep such books or record and produce it on demand, the said dealer shall forfeit his license. <sidenote>Junk dealers, certain cities and towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Records to be kept.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P39" no="GA1923.2.42" />

<p>Paragraph 66. Legerdemain and Sleight of Hand. Upon each exhibition of feats of legerdemain or sleight of hand, or other exhibition and entertainment of like kind, $25.00 in each county. <sidenote>Legerdemain and sleight of hand.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 67. Lighting Systems. Upon each person, firm or corporation selling, whether as manufacturer, agent or dealer in, any lighting system, whether gas, gasoline or electrical, $25.00 in each county. <sidenote>Lighting systems.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 68. Lightning Rods. Upon each person, firm or corporation who may contract for or engage in the business of fitting up or erecting lightning rods in this State, the sum of $50.00 for each county in which he may contract for, or erect, or put in place any lightning rod, or rods, upon any structure or building therein, and it shall be the duty of the tax collector to whom the tax is paid to issue the person paying such tax a license receipt, showing such payment. <sidenote>Lightning rods.</sidenote> <sidenote>Duty as to receipts.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 69. Live Stock Dealers. Upon each person, firm or corporation dealing in live stock, having a fixed place of business in or near cities of more than 50,000 inhabitants, $25.00; in or near cities of from 10,000 to 50,000 inhabitants, $15.00; in or near cities or towns of less than 10,000 inhabitants, $10.00. <sidenote>Live stock dealers; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 70. Loan Agents. Upon each person, firm or corporation negotiating loans and charging therefor any fee, commission or salary, in each county in which he or they may carry on such business, the sum of $25.00. Provided, This tax shall not be required of attorneys-at-law who have paid the professional tax imposed by Paragraph 3 of this section, and who shall engage in negotiating loans on collateral other than wages, time or salary. Provided further, That this tax shall not be required of any person, firm or corporation in any county in which its correspondents, agents, or other local representative has paid said tax, or otherwise complied with or conformed to this section. <sidenote>Loan agents.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to application of Act.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P40" no="GA1923.2.43" />

<p>(b) Should such person, firm or corporation engage in making or negotiating loans upon wages or time, or the purchasing of salaries, the sum of $100.00. <sidenote>Additional tax.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 71. Legislative Agents. Upon each person registered under the Act of the General Assembly approved August 11, 1911 (See Acts 1911, Page 151), the sum of $100.00. <sidenote>Legislative agents.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 72. Laundries. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating a laundry or dyeing establishment, $100.00 if employing ten or more persons; $50.00, if employing five and not more than ten persons; $25.00 if not employing more than five persons. <sidenote>Laundries.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 73. Machines (Store Cash Registers). Upon each manufacturer or wholesale dealer in, or agent for the sale of any cash or account register, $100.00 for each place of business in this State. <sidenote>Cash registers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 74. Machines (Weighing or Calculating). Upon each manufacturer or wholesale or retail dealer in, or agent for the manufacturer of any weighing scale, or scales, for calculating weight or prices of commodities, $25.00 for each place of business in this State. <sidenote>Scales, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 75. Machines (Adding Machines). Upon every manufacturer of, or wholesale or retail dealer in, or agent for the sale of any adding or calculating machine retailing for more than ten dollars, $100.00 for each place of business in this State. <sidenote>Adding machines.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 76. Machines (Typewriters). Upon every manufacturer of, or wholesale or retail dealer in, or agent for the sale of any typewriter or typewriting machine, $100.00 for each place of business in this State. <sidenote>Typewriters.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 77. Machines (Slot). Upon every machine, punchboard or other device, operated, used or kept in this State wherein is kept any article to be purchased by depositing therein or paid therefor any coin or thing of

<page id="GA1923.2.P41" no="GA1923.2.44" />

value, and for which may be had any article of merchandise whatsoever, where there is no chance incurred by reason thereof and where the deposit of coin or other thing of value does not exceed one cent per operation, $2.00 for each machine, punchboard or other device for each county where kept, set up, used or operated. <sidenote>Slot machines</sidenote> <sidenote>For sale of merchandise.</sidenote></p><p>(b) Upon each slot machine wherein may be seen any picture or music may be heard by depositing in said machine any coin or thing of value, and each weighing machine or scale, and every machine making stencils by the use of contrivances operated by slot wherein coin or other thing of value is to be deposited or used, the deposit of coin or other thing of value not exceeding one cent per operation, $1.00 for each county where kept, set up, used or operated. On all other machines described in this paragraph, charging more than one cent per operation, $5.00 for each county where kept, set up, used or operated. Provided, That not more than $100.00 shall be required of any one person in any one county under this paragraph. Provided, further, That no machine described in this paragraph shall be subject to more than one tax. <sidenote>Picture, music, weighing, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Charging more than one cent.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to limit.</sidenote> <sidenote>One tax per machine.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 78. Bicycle Dealers. Upon every bicycle dealer selling or dealing in bicycles, either at wholesale or retail, for themselves, or upon commission, or consignments, $10.00 for the fiscal year or part thereof. Dealers selling bicycles at more than one place shall pay license for each place of business. All unsold bicycles belonging to dealers shall be liable to seizure and sale for payment of such tax. <sidenote>Bicycle dealers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 79. Motorcycle Dealers. Upon every person, firm or corporation selling or dealing in motorcycles or motor attachments for bicycles, whether in connection with the business of selling bicycles or automobiles or otherwise, $25.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Motorcycle dealers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 80. Machinery and Equipments. Upon every manufacturer of reaping, mowing, binding, or threshing

<page id="GA1923.2.P42" no="GA1923.2.45" />

machines, gas, electrical or oil engines, agricultural machinery propelled by gas, and road building machinery propelled by gas or oil, culverts, road machines and road graders, selling or dealing in such machinery by itself or its agents in this State, and all wholesale and retail dealers in the above mentioned machinery, selling such machinery manufactured by companies that have not paid the tax thereon named, shall pay $100.00 annually to the Comptroller-General at the time of commencement of business, same to be known as a license fee for the privilege of doing business in this State. All companies and others paying this license fee shall, at the time of payment, furnish the Comptroller-General with a list of all agents authorized to sell the aforesaid machinery of their manufacture, or under their control, and shall pay to said Comptroller-General the sum of $10.00 for each of said agents for the fiscal year or fractional part thereof for each county in which the said agents may do business; upon the payment of $10.00 the Comptroller-General shall issue to each of said agents a certificate of authority to transact business in this State. Before commencing business in this State all such agents shall be required to register their names with the ordinaries of those counties in which they intend to do business, and shall exhibit to said ordinaries their license from the Comptroller-General; wholesale and retail dealers in the above mentioned machinery shall be required to pay tax provided herein for manufacturers of the above machines sold by them unless said manufacturers have paid the tax required by this Act. All unsold machinery belonging to manufacturers, dealers, or other agents, or in their possession or the possession of others, shall be liable to seizure and sale for the payment of such fees, license or tax. None of the provisions of this paragraph shall apply to licensed auctioneers selling second-hand machinery, or to officers of the law under legal process, or to merchants buying or selling said machinery on which a license tax has been paid as herein provided, and who keep the same and sell and

<page id="GA1923.2.P43" no="GA1923.2.46" />

deliver them from their place of business. Any person who shall violate the provisions of this paragraph shall be liable to prosecution for a misdemeanor and on conviction shall be punished as prescribed in Section 1065, Volume 2 of the Code of 1910. <sidenote>Machinery and equipment; manufacturers.</sidenote> <sidenote>Wholesale and retail dealers.</sidenote> <sidenote>Tax for each agent.</sidenote> <sidenote>Certificate of authority for Comptroller-General.</sidenote> <sidenote>Wholesale and retail dealers must pay tax if manufacturer does not.</sidenote> <sidenote>Unsold goods seized for nonpayment.</sidenote> <sidenote>Persons to whom these provisions do not apply.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty for violation.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 81. Merry-Go-Rounds. Upon the owner, manager, keeper or lessee of any merry-go-round or flying horses, or flying swings, or human roulettes, or scenic devices run by machinery, or of any elevated railway or scenic railway, or similar contrivance kept for gain, either directly or indirectly, for each place of business in this State, and for each place where operated, in or near cities over 50,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in or near cities between 10,000 and 50,000, $30.00; in or near cities between 5,000 and 10,000, $20.00; and in or near cities or towns less than 5,000 inhabitants, $10.00. <sidenote>Merry-go-rounds; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 82. Motion Picture Supply House. Upon all motion picture supply houses, or film distributing agencies, $100.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Motion picture supply houses.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 83. Musical Instruments, Graphophones, Organs, Phonographs, Pianos and Victrolas. Upon each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of selling or renting, as agents or dealers, any of the above or similar instruments, in or near cities of more than 50,000 inhabitants, $100.00; in or near cities of from 25,000 to 50,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in or near cities of from 10,000 to 25,000, $25.00; in or near cities or towns of less than 10,000, $10.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Musical instruments; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 84. News Dealers. Upon each person, firm or corporation carrying on the business of selling books, magazines, papers, fruits, confections or other articles of merchandise on the railroad trains in this State, $500.00. No county or municipality shall have authority to levy any additional tax for the privilege of carrying on said business. <sidenote>News dealers.</sidenote> <sidenote>No additional tax.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P44" no="GA1923.2.47" />

<p>Paragraph 85. Packing House. Upon every individual agent or firm of agents of any packing house, and upon any and every individual agent or firm of agents of any person, firm or corporation dealing in any packing house products or goods, doing business in this State, for each place of business in each county having a city situated therein with a population of 30,000 or more, $300.00; for each place of business in each county with a population of from 15,000 to 30,000, $150.00; for each place of business in each county with a population of from 5,000 to 15,000, $50.00; for each place of business in each county with a population of less than 5,000, $25.00. <sidenote>Packing houses; certain counties.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 86. Pawn Brokers. Upon each person, firm or corporation carrying on the business of pawn brokers, for each place of business in this State, $200.00. If any pawn broker shall sell, or offer for sale, or expose in his place of business any pistol, pistol or rifle cartridges, dirk, bowie knife or metal knucks, whether sold as unredeemed pledges, or otherwise, he shall also be held subject to and required to pay the license tax required of the dealers in such articles by Paragraph 92 of this section of this Act. <sidenote>Pawn brokers.</sidenote> <sidenote>Also liable to tax as dealer.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 87. Photographers. Upon every daguerrean, ambrotype, photographic and similar artists carrying on the business of making pictures, securing negatives for pictures to be made elsewhere than in the county of his bona fide residence, $10.00. <sidenote>Photographers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 88. Peddlers. Upon every peddler or travelling vendor of any patent or proprietary medicine or remedies, or appliances of any kind or special nostrum, or jewelry, or stationery, or drugs, or soap, or of any other kind of merchandise or commodity whatsoever (whether herein enumerated or not), peddling or selling any such goods or articles, or other merchandise in each county where the same or any of them are peddled, sold or offered for sale, $50.00. <sidenote>Peddlers or travelling vendors, medicines, jewelry. stationery, soap, etc.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P45" no="GA1923.2.48" />

<p><list><item><p>(b) Upon every peddler of stoves or ranges for cooking purposes, or clocks, or albums, or picture frames, for each county wherein he may sell or offer for sale either of said articles, $25.00. <sidenote>Stoves, ranges, clocks, etc.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(c) Upon any travelling vendor of any patent churn, or patented fence, or patented agricultural implements, or tools, or other patented articles, $25.00 for each county in which he may sell or offer to sell either of the enumerated articles. <sidenote>Patented churns, fences, agricultural implements, etc.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>(d) Upon every travelling vendor using boats, barges, or other water craft for the purpose of selling goods of any kind, not prohibited by law, on the rivers or waters within the limits of this State, for each county where he may sell such wares, goods or merchandise, $50.00. The tax shall be a lien upon the boat, barge or other water craft, and its contents, without regard to the ownership thereof. <sidenote>Use of boats, barges, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Lien on equipment and stock.</sidenote></p></item></list></p><p>Paragraph 89. Pictures or Picture Frames. Upon every person, firm or corporation who, in person or through its agent, sells and delivers photographs or pictures of any character, or picture frames, whether they make charge for such frames or not, $15.00 in each county in which this business is done. Provided, This shall not apply to regular merchants dealing in such goods at their usual place of business. <sidenote>Pictures and picture frames.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to certain merchants.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 90. Monument Dealers. Upon each firm or corporation selling monuments or tombstones, $25.00 in each county in which they shall have a place of business. <sidenote>Monument dealers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 91. Moving Pictures and Vaudeville Performances. Upon each and every electric show or exhibition of moving pictures, or illustrated songs, except where given for educational purposes, and upon each place where vaudeville performances are given, whether with or without electric show or moving pictures, for each place of business in or near towns of less than 2,000 inhabitants, $2.00 per month; in or near cities from 2,000 to 5,000 inhabitants,

<page id="GA1923.2.P46" no="GA1923.2.49" />

$2.00 per month; in or near cities from 5,000 to 10,000 inhabitants, $7.00 per month; in or near cities from 10,000 to 25,000 inhabitants, $10.00 per month; in or near cities from 25,000 to 50,000 inhabitants, $12.50 per month; and in cities of 50,000 or more inhabitants, $25.00 per month, except in suburbs of cities of more than 50,000, where such tax shall be $12.50 per month. <sidenote>Moving pictures and vaudeville performances; certain towns and cities.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 92. Pistols. Upon each and every dealer in pistols or in toy pistols which shoot cartridges, or who deal in pistol cartridges, or rifle cartridges, dirks, bowie knives or metal knucks, for each place of business in this State in or near towns or cities of 10,000 or less inhabitants, $50.00; in or near cities of over 10,000, $100.00. Provided, further, That no Confederate veteran, indigent person or any firm or corporation shall be exempt from this tax. <sidenote>Pistols, cartridges, dirks, etc.; certain cities and towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to non-exemption.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 93. Safes and Vaults. Upon all agents or agencies selling safes or vaults, or vault doors or other vault fixtures, $100.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Safes and vaults.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 94. Sanatoriums. Upon hospitals and sanatoriums, or institutions of like character, whether incorporated or not, conducted for gain in or near cities of more than 20,000 population, $100.00. In or near cities or towns of less than 20,000, $25.00. Provided, The above tax shall not apply to public hospitals maintained by municipal corporations for charitable purposes only. <sidenote>Sanatoriums; certain cities or towns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to charitable institutions.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 95. Soda Fountains. Upon each person, firm or corporation running or operating soda fountains in this State, having one draught arm or similar device used in drawing carbonated water, $5.00; and for each additional arm or device, $5.00. <sidenote>Soda fountains.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 96. Soft Drink Syrups. Upon all persons and companies carrying on, in this State, the business of manufacturing or selling, by wholesale or retail, or distributing from any depot, car or warehouse or agency, any carbonated waters or syrups or other articles to be used

<page id="GA1923.2.P47" no="GA1923.2.50" />

in carbonated water, or intended to be fixed with or blended with carbonated water to be sold as soft drinks (not including imitations of beer, wine, whiskey or other intoxicating liquors), as an occupation tax for the privilege of carrying on said business, an amount payable at the end of each quarter, an amount equal to one-half one per cent (%) of the gross receipts from said business for said quarter in this State. Within three days from the end of each quarter of the calender year each person or company engaged in said kind of business shall make returns under oath to the Comptroller-General of this State, showing the amount of said gross receipts with a detailed statement of the parties from whom said receipts are received. <sidenote>Soft drink syrups.</sidenote> <sidenote>Imitations of beer, wine, etc., not included.</sidenote> <sidenote>Amount of tax.</sidenote> <sidenote>Quarterly returns to be made under oath.</sidenote></p><p>In case a corporation, the return shall be made under oath by the president, if a resident of this State, and if the president is not such resident, by the officer or person in charge of the business of said corporation in this State. Upon failure of any person required by this paragraph to make such returns within ten days after the expiration of such quarter, he shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be liable to prosecution and be punished as now provided in cases of misdemeanor. Upon the making of such returns, the person or company liable to said tax shall pay the same to the Comptroller-General, and upon failure to pay the same, the Comptroller-General shall issue an execution for said tax against the property of the person or company liable to said tax. If no returns be made or if the Comptroller-General believes said returns are false, the Comptroller-General shall ascertain the amount of said gross receipts from the best information in his power and assess the tax accordingly, after giving the company or person liable to said tax at least five days' notice of the time of assessing said tax, and issue his execution accordingly against the person or corporation carrying on said business. Any person, company or agent carrying on any kind of business specified in this paragraph, after failure to

<page id="GA1923.2.P48" no="GA1923.2.51" />

pay the tax herein levied for any preceding quarter during which he or it was liable to tax, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor. It is hereby enacted that all of said taxes received or collected under this paragraph shall be paid into the State Treasury. It is also enacted that any person or company paying the tax herein levied shall be relieved of any and all occupation tax or license fees to the State under existing laws on or for the kind of business specified in this paragraph. Provided, however, that said tax shall be collected upon said syrup or carbonated water only once, and shall be paid by the wholesale dealer in said syrup if sold within the confines of this State by such wholesale dealer; and if said syrup or carbonated water shall be purchased by the retail dealer without the limits of this State and shall be shipped to a point within the limits of this State, the same shall be taxed in the hands of such retail dealer, and for the purposes of this tax the price paid for such syrup or carbonated water shall determine the receipts for the same. <sidenote>Returns to be made by whom.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty for failure to make returns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Issue of execution on failure to pay tax.</sidenote> <sidenote>Assessment by Comptroller-General.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty for failure to pay tax.</sidenote> <sidenote>Pay into State Treasury.</sidenote> <sidenote>Relief of other occupation tax or license fees.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to who shall pay tax under these provisions.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 97. Hotels. Upon every person, firm or corporation operating a hotel in counties of over 30,000 inhabitants, a tax of $1.00 for each sleeping room per annum, and in counties of less than 30,000 inhabitants, 50 cents per annum for each sleeping room. <sidenote>Hotels; certain counties.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 98. Cafes and Restaurants. Upon every person, firm or corporation, except hotels, operating any cafe, restaurant or lunch room with five or more tables, $10.00; ten or more tables, $25.00; twenty-five tables or more, $50.00; fifty tables or more, $100.00. <sidenote>Cafes and restaurants.</sidenote></p><p>Provided, however, That four seats or stools shall be construed to constitute a table. <sidenote>Proviso defining tables.</sidenote></p><p>On all persons engaged in operating wiener stands, in towns or cities of a population of 20,000 or less, $5.00 for each such place of business; in cities of more than 20,000 population, $10.00 for each such place of business. <sidenote>Wiener stands; certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P49" no="GA1923.2.52" />

<p>Paragraph 99. Street Carnival. Upon every midway combination of small shows, or street fair or street carnival, the sum of $25.00 each week or fractional part thereof, for each separate tent, enclosure or place where an admission fee is charged or collected, either directly or indirectly, to witness or hear any performance, or where anything may be exhibited for admission or ticket; and upon every merrygo-round or flying horse, accompanying any midway combination, street fair or street carnival, in each city or town in this state in which it does business, or in each county where they may operate outside of the limits of any city or town in this State, $25.00. Provided, That should the said midway combination, or any of them specified above, be held in connection with county, district, or state agricultural fairs of this State and under the direction of, and within the grounds at the time of holding said fairs, the whole amount of said tax for said attraction when so held shall be $25.00 per week or a fractional part thereof. <sidenote>Street carnivals.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to connections with agricultural fairs.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 100. Tank and Pumping Systems. Upon each person, firm or corporation selling or dealing in tanks and pumps, or tanks or pumps for oil, gasoline or kerosene, or other like fluids, $50.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Tank and pumping systems.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 101. Trading Stamps. Upon all trading stamp companies, or dealers in trading stamps, $50.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Trading stamps.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 102. Steamship Companies. Upon all steamship and steamboat companies located in this State, $100.00. <sidenote>Steamship companies.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 103. Undertaking. Upon each person, firm or corporation whose business is that of burying the dead and charging for same, commonly known as undertakers, in or near cities of more than 50,000 inhabitants, $200.00; in or near cities from 10,000 to 50,000 inhabitants, $100.00; in or near cities from 5,000 to 10,000 inhabitants, $50.00; in or near cities or towns of from 2,500 to 5,00 inhabitants.

<page id="GA1923.2.P50" no="GA1923.2.53" />

$20.00; in or near towns of less than 2,500 inhabitants, $10.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Undertaking: certain cities and towns.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 104. Warehouses, Cotton. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating a warehouse or yard for the storage and handling of cotton for compensation license tax is as follows: Where not less than 500 or more than 5,000 bales are handled in one year, $10.00; where not less than 5,000 nor more than 10,000 bales are handled in one year, $25.00; where not less than 10,000 nor more than 20,000 bales are handled in one year, $50.00; where not less than 20,000 bales, nor more than 30,000 bales are handled in one year $100.00; where more than 30,000 bales are handled in one year, $200.00. <sidenote>Cotton warehouses.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 105. Warehouses, Merchandise, etc. Upon each person, firm or corporation operating a warehouse or yard for storage of goods, wares or merchandise and farm products other than cotton and charging for the same, $25.00. Provided, That any warehouse that pays taxes as provided by Paragraph 104 of this section shall not be subject to tax required by this paragraph. <sidenote>Merchandise warehouses.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to exception of cotton warehouses, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 106. Waterworks. Upon each person, firm or corporation dealing in, as manufacturers of or agents for, any waterworks system, whether the power operating same is derived from a wind mill, hydraulic, gas, or similar engine or electrical apparatus, the sum of $100.00 in each county wherein such business is carried on. <sidenote>Waterworks.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 107. Dealers in Fish. Upon each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of packing or shipping oysters, shrimp or fish, $50.00 for each county. <sidenote>Dealers in fish, etc.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 108. Patent Rights. Upon each person, firm or corporation selling patent rights in Georgia, the sum of $50.00 for each county in which said business is carried on. <sidenote>Patent rights.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 109. Commercial Reporting Agencies. Upon

<page id="GA1923.2.P51" no="GA1923.2.54" />

each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of a commercial reporting agency, in each county in the State where they have an office or branch office, $125.00. <sidenote>Commercial reporting agents.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 110. Stevedores. Upon each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of a stevedore, the sum of $100.00 for each place of business. <sidenote>Stevedores.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 111. Salary and Wage Buyers. Upon each person, firm or corporation or partnership buying salary or wage accounts and all negotiable papers, $100.00 for each office and place of business maintained. <sidenote>Salary and wage buyers.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 112. Carbonic Acid Gas. Each person, firm or corporation engaged in the business of manufacturing or vending soft drinks made of or containing carbonic acid gas or any substitute therefor shall pay as a privilege license to carry on such business 4 cents on each pound of carbonic acid gas, or any substitute therefor so used. Provided, that bottled drinks on which this license shall have been paid may be resold in original packages without the payment of any further license under this schedule. Each person, firm or corporation engaged in such business shall keep accurate books and invoices showing the quantity of carbonic acid gas or any substitute therefor used in such business, and such other information relating to the business as may be required by the Comptroller General to enable the state tax officials to check up the returns herein required. At the end of each calendar quarterly period every person, firm or corporation engaged in such business shall make a report to the Comptroller General on blanks to be furnished by the Comptroller General, showing the amount of carbonic acid gas or other substitute therefor, consumed during the preceding quarter, and such other information as the Comptroller General may require, verified by affidavit, and shall with such report remit the license herein provided for each pound of carbonic acid gas or other substitute therefor consumed, as shown by the report, and such remittance shall be paid into the State treasury.

<page id="GA1923.2.P52" no="GA1923.2.55" />

If such report and remittance is not made within fifteen days after the end of the calendar quarter, there shall be added to the sum due for such license for the preceding quarter, ten per cent additional license. The tax officials of the State shall have authority to examine the books and papers of any one engaged in such business for the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of all reports and remittances. Any person wilfully failing or refusing to make the reports and remittances herein required shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and any person wilfully making a false affidavit as to any report herein required shall be guilty of perjury. <sidenote>Carbonic acid gas.</sidenote> <sidenote>Amount of tax.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to resale in original packages.</sidenote> <sidenote>Keeping of books, invoices, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Quarterly reports verified by affidavit.</sidenote> <sidenote>Remittance to State Treasury.</sidenote> <sidenote>Ten per cent added for delay in payment.</sidenote> <sidenote>Verification of reports, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty for failure to make report and remittance and making false affidavit.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 113. Toll Bridges and Ferries. Upon all persons or corporations operating ferries, $15.00. Upon all persons or corporations operating toll bridges, $100.00, said tax to be paid to the collector of the county in which the owner lives or is domiciled. Provided, That this tax shall not be required of any ferry or toll bridge, the receipts from which do not amount to more than $500.00 per annum. <sidenote>Toll bridges and ferries.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to certain exemptions.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 114. Beauty Parlors, etc. Upon each beauty parlor or shop, or manicure shop, $10.00 for each place of business. Provided, That this tax shall not apply to manicure shops, operated in connection with barber shops. <sidenote>Beauty parlors, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso excepting.</sidenote></p><p>Paragraph 115. Swimming Pools. Upon each and every person, firm or corporation operating a swimming pool where admission fees are charged, or upon persons, firms or corporations keeping and renting bathing suits for hire, $20.00 in counties of over 50,000 population, and $10.00 in counties of under 50,000 population; upon persons, firms or corporations conducting or operating a bathing resort in or near the ocean and ocean and gulf front of this State for hire, the sum of $200.00 in each county where such bathing resort is located. <sidenote>Swimming pools and bathing resorts, etc.; certain counties.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 3. Dogs. All dogs are hereby made personal property and shall be given in and taxed as other property of this State is given in and taxed, such tax to be enforced

<page id="GA1923.2.P53" no="GA1923.2.56" />

by levy and sales as other taxes are collected and not to interfere with the imposition and collection of any municipal taxes on dogs, whether such dog or dogs be owned by the tax payer, his wife or minor children. <sidenote>Dogs.</sidenote> <sidenote>Tax as personal property.</sidenote> <sidenote>Non-interference with municipal taxes.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 4. Sewing Machines. Upon every sewing machine company selling or dealing in sewing machines by itself or its agents in this State, and all wholesale and retail dealers in sewing machines, selling machines manufactured by companies that have not paid the tax herein, $400.00 for each fiscal year of fraction thereof, to be paid to the Comptroller-General at the time of commencement of business, and said companies or dealers shall furnish the Comptroller-General with a list of agents authorized to sell machines of their manufacture or under their control, and shall pay to said Comptroller-General the sum of $10.00 for each of said agents for the fiscal year or fractional part thereof, for each county in which said agents do business for said company. Upon the payment of said additional sum the Comptroller-General shall issue to each of said agents a certificate of authority to transact business in this State. Before doing business under this Act, all sewing machine agents shall be required to register their names with the ordinaries of those counties in which they intend to operate and exhibit to said ordinaries their license from the Comptroller-General, and to keep such license posted on their vehicles, or at their place of business. Wholesale and retail dealers in sewing machines shall be required to pay the tax provided herein for each manufacturer of sewing machines sold by them, except where the tax required by this Act has been paid by said manufacturer. All unsold sewing machines belonging to sewing machine companies, dealers, or their agents, in possession of said companies, dealers, their agents or others, shall be liable to seizure and sale for payment of such fees, license or tax. Any person who shall violate the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction shall be punished as prescribed in Section 1065, Volume 2, of the

<page id="GA1923.2.P54" no="GA1923.2.57" />

Code of 1910. None of the provisions of this section shall apply to licensed auctioneers selling second-hand sewing machines, or to officers of the law under legal process, or to merchants buying and selling machines on which a license tax has been paid as herein provided, and who keep the machines and sell and deliver them at their places of business, such sales not being on commission. Provided, That if said merchant shall employ an agent or agents to deliver or sell the machines, the provisions of this Act shall apply to said agent or agents. <sidenote>Sewing machines, manufacturers.</sidenote> <sidenote>Wholesale and retail dealers.</sidenote> <sidenote>Tax for each agent.</sidenote> <sidenote>Certificate of authority for Comptroller-General.</sidenote> <sidenote>Wholesale and retail dealers must pay if manufacturer does not.</sidenote> <sidenote>Unsold goods seized for non-payment</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty for violation.</sidenote> <sidenote>Persons to whom these provisions do not apply.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to agents.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 5. Taxes, How Returned. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the tax provided for in Section 4 requires return made to the Comptroller-General in accordance with the law of Georgia. The tax required by Paragraphs 3 and 4 of Section 2 of this Act, shall be returned to the receiver of tax returns in the county of the residence of the person liable to such tax and shall be entered by the receiver upon the digest of taxable property. In the case of the tax imposed upon Foreign Corporations by Paragraph 49 of Section 2, and the tax imposed by Paragraph 80 manufacturers of machinery and implements; upon soft drink syrups by Paragraph 96, and upon carbonic acid gas by Paragraph 112, the return is required to be made, and the tax paid to the Comptroller-General. The tax imposed upon legislative agents by Paragraph 71 of Section 2 shall be paid to the Secretary of State when each person registers, and he shall not be allowed to register until such tax is paid. All other taxes enumerated and set forth in Section 2 of this Act shall be returned and paid to the tax collector of the county where such vocations are carried on. <sidenote>Tax returns; general rules governing.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 6. Taxes, How Paid. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the taxes provided for in this Act shall be paid in full for the fiscal year for which they are levied, and except where otherwise provided, said taxes shall be paid to the tax collectors of the counties where such

<page id="GA1923.2.P55" no="GA1923.2.58" />

vocations are carried on, at the time of commencing to do business. Before any person shall be authorized to open up or carry on said business, they shall go before the ordinary of the county in which they propose to do business and register their names, the business they propose to engage in, the place where it is to be conducted; and they shall then proceed to pay the tax to the collector, and it shall be the duty of the said ordinary to immediately notify the tax collector of such registration, and at the end of each quarter to furnish the Comptroller-General with a report of such special tax registration in his office. Any person failing to register with the ordinary or, having registered, failing to pay the special tax as herein required, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction shall be fined not less than double the tax, or be imprisoned, as prescribed by Section 1065 of Volume 2 of the Code of 1910, or both, in the discretion of the court; one-half of said fine shall be applied to the payment of the tax and the other to the fund of fines and forfeitures for the use of the officers of the court. Provided, however, That in all counties of this State where the officers of the superior court, or city court, are now or may hereafter be upon the salary basis, the other half of the fine shall be paid into the treasury of such counties and shall become the property of such counties. <sidenote>Tax payments; how and when made.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalty for non-payment.</sidenote> <sidenote>Disposition of fine.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to certain counties.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 7. Insurance Companies. (1) Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That all foreign and domestic insurance companies doing business in this State shall pay one and one-half (1%) per cent upon gross premiums received by them in this State for the year, with no deduction for dividends, whether returned in cash or allowed in payment or reduction of premiums, or for additional insurance; nor shall any deduction be allowed for premium abatements of any kind or character, or for reinsurance, except companies doing business in Georgia, or for cash surrender values paid, or for losses, or expenses of any kind, said tax being imposed upon gross premiums without any deductions whatever except for premiums returned

<page id="GA1923.2.P56" no="GA1923.2.59" />

on change of rate and cancelled policies and on reinsurance as above provided. Provided, That local organizations known as Farmers' Mutual Insurance Companies, operating in not more than four counties, shall not be subject to this tax. Provided, further, That mutual fire insurance companies chartered by this State which require their members to make premium deposits to provide for losses and expenses, and which premium deposits are used wholly for the payment of losses and expenses and returned to the policyholders or held to pay losses and expenses and as reinsurance reserves, shall not be subject to this tax. <sidenote>Insurance companies; foreign and domestic.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to certain local organizations and mutual fire insurance companies.</sidenote></p><p>(2) Every insurance company incorporated under the laws of this State and doing business on the legal reserve plan, shall be required to return for taxation all of its real estate as other real estate is returned, and all of the personal property owned by it shall be ascertained in the following manner: From the total value of the assets held by the company, both real and personal, shall be deducted the assessed value of all real estate owned by the company in this State, the non-taxable funds deposited by the company with the State Treasurer, and the amount of the reserve or net value of the policies required by law to be held by the company for its policyholders, and which belong to such policyholders; the remainder shall be the value of the personal property owned by and taxable against such companies. <sidenote>Return of real estate and personal property.</sidenote> <sidenote>How value of personal property found.</sidenote></p><p>(3) That whenever any insurance company doing business in this State shall make it appear by proof to the Insurance Commissioners that one-fourth of the total assets are invested in any or all of the following securities or property, to wit: Bonds of this State, or of any county or municipality of this State, property situated in this State and taxable therein, loans secured by liens on real estate situated in this State, or policy loans by insurance policies issued by such company on lives of persons resident of this State, then the premium tax levied by the first paragraph

<page id="GA1923.2.P57" no="GA1923.2.60" />

of this section shall be abated or reduced to one per centum upon the gross receipts of such company, and if the amounts so invested by any such company shall be as much as three-fourths of the total assets of such company, then said premium tax shall be abated or reduced to one-fourth of one per centum upon such gross receipts of such company. <sidenote>When premium tax abated.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 8. Manufacturing Companies. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the president, superintendent or agents of all manufacturing and other companies, whether incorporated or not (other than railroad, telegraph, telephone, express, sleeping and palace car companies, and such other companies as are required to make return of the value of their franchise to the Comptroller-General under the provisions of the Act approved December 17th, 1902, entitled an Act to provide for and require the payment of taxes on franchises, and to provide the method for the return and payment of said taxes), and all persons and companies conducting business enterprises of every nature whatsoever, shall return for taxation at its true market value all of their real estate to the tax receiver of the county wherein said real estate is located. Provided, That if the real estate upon which said manufacturing or other business enterprise of whatsoever nature is carried on, lies on or across the county line, or county lines, and in two or more counties, said real estate shall be returned to the tax receiver of the county wherein are located the main buildings containing the machinery, or most of the main buildings. Provided, further, That all persons, companies and corporations not excepted above, conducting any business enterprise upon realty not taxable in the county in which such persons reside or the office of the company or corporation is located, shall return for taxation their stock of merchandise, raw materials, machinery, live stock, and all other personalty employed in the operation of such business enterprises, together with the manufactured goods and all other property of such business enterprises and notes and accounts made and the money used in the prosecution

<page id="GA1923.2.P58" no="GA1923.2.61" />

of such business enterprises on hand at the time for the estimation of property for taxation, including all personalty of whatsoever kind connected with or used in such enterprises in any manner whatsoever, in the county in which is taxable the realty wherein such business enterprises are located or carried on. Provided, further, That the agent in this State of any person, firm or corporation resident without this State who shall have on hand and for sale, storage or otherwise as such agents, merchandise or other property, including money, notes, accounts, bonds, stocks, etc., shall return the same for taxation to the tax receiver of the county wherein the same may be taxed for State and county purposes as other property in this State is taxed. The word merchandise shall be held to include guano, commercial fertilizer, save and except that all canal and slack-water navigation companies shall make through their respective executive officers or stockholders in possession of the same, returns to the tax receiver of each county in which the same is located, or through which the same shall pass, in whole or in part of the right-of-way, locks and dams, toll houses, structures, and all other real estate owned by or used by the company or stockholders thereof. Provided, That this Act shall not make subject to taxation any property of canal or navigation companies which is not subject to taxation by the laws of this State now existing. The president of every manufacturing company in this State, and agent, general manager or person in possession or charge of the business and property in this State of any non-resident person, firm or corporation, shall be required to answer under oath in addition to those provided by law, the following questions: <sidenote>Manufacturing companies.</sidenote> <sidenote>Companies excepted.</sidenote> <sidenote>Real estate tax return.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to location of real estate.</sidenote> <sidenote>All personal property to be returned for taxation.</sidenote> <sidenote>Agent of non-resident must make return.</sidenote> <sidenote>Merchandise defined.</sidenote> <sidenote>Returns of canal and slack water navigation companies.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to certain exemptions.</sidenote> <sidenote>Who shall answer the following questions.</sidenote></p><p><list><item><p>1. What is the true market value of the real estate of the company you represent, including the buildings thereon? <sidenote>Market value of real estate including buildings.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>2. What is the true market value of your machinery of every kind? <sidenote>Market value of machinery.</sidenote></p></item>

<page id="GA1923.2.P59" no="GA1923.2.62" />

<item><p>3. What is the true market value of the real estate not used in the conduct of the business of your company? <sidenote>Market value of real estate not used.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>4. What is the true market value of raw materials on hand on the day fixed for return of property for taxation? <sidenote>Market value of raw materials.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>5. What is the true market value of manufactured goods or articles on hand on the day for the return of property for taxation, whether at your principal office or in the hands of agents, commission merchants or others? <sidenote>Market value of manufactured goods.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>6. How much money did your company have on hand the day fixed for the return of property for taxation, whether within or without the State? How much deposited in bank? <sidenote>Amount of money on hand.</sidenote></p></item><item><p>7. State separately the true market value of the notes, bonds, and other obligations for money or property of every kind on hand on the day fixed for the return of property for taxation. And such company shall be taxed upon its entire property, so ascertained, and the Comptroller-General is authorized to frame and have propounded any other questions which in his judgment will produce a fuller return. <sidenote>Market value of notes, bonds, etc.</sidenote> <sidenote>Anti-property tax; Comptroller-General's authority.</sidenote></p></item></list></p><p>Sec. 9. Railroads, Return to Whom Made. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That all railroad companies, street and suburban railroads or sleeping car companies or persons or companies operating railroads or street railroads, or suburban railroads or sleeping cars in this State, all express companies, including railroad companies doing an express, telephone or telegraph business, and all telephone and telegraph companies, person, or persons, doing an express, telephone or telegraph business; all gas, water, electric light or power, steam, heat, refrigerated air, dockage or cranage, canal toll road, toll bridges, railroads, equipment and navigation companies, through their president, general manager, or agent having control of the company's offices in this State, shall be required to make returns of all property of said company located in this State to the Comptroller-General, and the laws now in

<page id="GA1923.2.P60" no="GA1923.2.63" />

force providing for the taxation of railroads in this State, shall be applicable to the assessments of taxes from said business as above stated. <sidenote>Railroads, express companies, etc.: required to make return of all property to Comptroller-General.</sidenote></p><p>2. Sleeping Car Companies. That each non-resident person or company whose sleeping cars are run in this State shall be taxed as follows: Ascertain the whole number of miles of railroads over which sleeping cars are run and ascertain the entire value of all sleeping cars of such person or company, then tax such sleeping cars at the regular tax rate imposed upon the property in this State in the same proportion to the entire value of such sleeping cars that the length of lines in this State over which such cars are run bear to the length of lines of all railroads over which such sleeping cars are run. The returns shall be made to the Comptroller-General by the president, general agent, agent or person in control of such cars in this State. The Comptroller-General shall frame such questions as will elicit the information sought, and answers thereto shall be made under oath. If the officers above referred to in control of said sleeping cars shall fail or refuse to answer, under oath, the questions propounded, the Comptroller-General shall obtain the information from such sources as he may, and he shall assess a double tax on such sleeping cars. If the taxes herein provided for are not paid, the Comptroller-General shall issue executions against the owners of such cars which may be levied by the sheriffs of any county in this State upon the sleeping car or cars of the owners, who have failed to pay the taxes. <sidenote>Sleeping car companies.</sidenote> <sidenote>How assessment is made.</sidenote> <sidenote>Who makes returns.</sidenote> <sidenote>Authority of Comptroller-General to question under oath, and assess a double tax in case of refusal to answer.</sidenote> <sidenote>Execution to issue on failure to pay.</sidenote></p><p>3. Equipment Companies. Any person or persons, co-partnerships, company or corporations, wherever organized or incorporated, owning or leasing or furnishing or operating any kind of railroad cars except dining, buffet, chair, parlor, palace, or sleeping cars, which cars are operated, or leased or hired to be operated, on any railroad in this State, shall be deemed an equipment company. <sidenote>Equipment companies defined.</sidenote> <sidenote>Exceptions.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P61" no="GA1923.2.64" />

<p>Every equipment company, as herein defined, shall be required to make returns to the Comptroller-General, and shall be taxed as follows: Ascertain the total number and the value of all cars of such equipment company, the total car wheel mileage made by said cars in the United States, and the total car wheel mileage in Georgia. Then tax such cars at the regular rate imposed upon property of this State in the same proportion to the entire value of such cars that the car wheel mileage made in Georgia bears to the entire car wheel mileage of said cars in the United States. The returns shall be made to the Comptroller-General by the president, general manager, agent, or person in control of such cars, and the Comptroller-General shall frame such questions as will elicit the information sought, and answers thereto shall be made under oath. If the officers above referred to in control of said cars shall fail or refuse to answer under oath the questions propounded, the Comptroller-General shall obtain the information from such sources as he may, and he shall assess a double tax on such cars. If the taxes herein provided are not paid, the Comptroller-General shall issue executions against said equipment company, which may be levied by the sheriff of any county in this State upon any car or cars owned, leased, or operated by the company failing to pay the tax. <sidenote>Returns made to whom, and method of assessment.</sidenote> <sidenote>Return made by whom.</sidenote> <sidenote>Authority to question under oath and double tax for failure to answer.</sidenote> <sidenote>Execution to issue on failure to pay.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 10. Railroad Returns and by Whom Made. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the presidents of all railroad companies doing business in this State shall make returns to the Comptroller-General in the manner provided by law for the taxation of the property or the gross receipts or net income of such railroads and shall pay the Comptroller-General the tax to which such property or gross receipts or net income may be subject according to the provisions of this Act, and the laws now in force relating to the tax on railroads, and on failure to make returns or refusals to pay tax, said company shall be liable to all the penalties now provided by law, and the Comptroller-General is hereby required upon failure of such companies

<page id="GA1923.2.P62" no="GA1923.2.65" />

to make returns, or if made and not satisfactory to said officer, to proceed against such companies as provided in Section 1050 of the Code of 1910, Volume 2. <sidenote>Railroad tax returns to be made by presidents of roads.</sidenote> <sidenote>Penalties and remedies where failure to make returns, or pay tax.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 11. Banks. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That no tax shall be assessed upon the capital of banks or banking associations organized under the authority of this State, or of the United States, located within this State, but the shares of the stockholders of the banks or banking associations, whether resident or nonresident owners, shall be taxed in the county where the bank or banking associations are located, and not elsewhere, at their full market value, including surplus and undivided profits, at the same rate provided in this Act for the taxation of other property in the hands of private individuals. Provided, That nothing in this section contained shall be construed to relieve such banks or banking associations from the tax on real estate held or owned by them, but they shall return said real estate at its true market value in the county where located. Provided, further, That where real estate is fully paid for, the value at which it is returned for taxation may be deducted from the market value of their shares and if said real estate is not fully paid for, only the value at which the equity owned by them therein is returned for taxation shall be deducted from the market value of their shares. The bank or banking associations themselves shall make the returns of the property and the shares therein mentioned and pay the taxes herein provided. Branch banks shall be taxed on the value of the capital employed in their operation, in the counties, municipalities, and districts in which they are located and the parent bank shall be relieved of taxation to the extent of the capital set aside for the exclusive use of such branches. <sidenote>Banks.</sidenote> <sidenote>No tax upon capital stock.</sidenote> <sidenote>Stockholders pay tax on each share at true market value.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to real holdings of bank.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to deduction of real estate values from stock values.</sidenote> <sidenote>Banks to make and pay taxes herein provided.</sidenote> <sidenote>Branch banks and certain relief of parent banks.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 12. Building and Loan Associations. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That mutual building and loan associations operating only in the county of their charter and limiting their loans to members, shall not be

<page id="GA1923.2.P63" no="GA1923.2.66" />

assessed on their capital loaned to stockholders or members thereof. All other building and loan associations or other associations of like character, shall be required to return to the tax receiver of the county where such associations are located all real and personal property of every kind and character belonging to such associations, except the real property located in another county shall be returned to the tax receiver of that county. <sidenote>Building and loan associations.</sidenote> <sidenote>Mutual associations.</sidenote> <sidenote>Other building and loan associations.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 13. Return by Resident Agents. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the president and principal agents of all incorporated companies herein mentioned, except such as are required to make returns to tax receivers of the counties, shall make returns to the Comptroller-General under the rules and regulations provided by law for such returns and subject to the same penalties and modes of procedure for the enforcement of taxes from companies or persons required by law to make returns to the Comptroller-General. <sidenote>Tax returns by resident agents.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 14. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, It shall be the duty of the sheriffs, their deputies and the constables of this State to look carefully after the collection of all taxes that may be due the State of Georgia under this Act, or any other special taxes due the State of Georgia. It shall be the duty of all tax collectors and sheriffs and constables of this State to direct and see that all persons, firms or corporations violating this Act or any of the tax acts of this State shall be prosecuted for all violations of the tax laws, and every person convicted for a violation of this Act or any of the special tax laws of Georgia, upon the information of any citizen of this State, one-fourth of the fine imposed upon any person for violation of the tax laws shall, by order of said court, be paid to such informant or prosecutor. <sidenote>Duties of sheriffs, deputy sheriffs, tax collectors, etc., as to collection of all taxes imposed under this Act.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 15. Be it further enacted, That wherever in any section or paragraph of this Act the words in towns or cities

<page id="GA1923.2.P64" no="GA1923.2.67" />

occur, the same shall be construed to mean within one mile of villages, towns, or cities, unless otherwise specified. <sidenote>In towns or cities defined.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 16. Be it further enacted, That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this Act be, and the same are, hereby repealed. <sidenote>Conflicting laws repealed.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 19, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1923V2N005" initial.page="67"><shorttitle>CERTAIN INDUSTRIES EXEMPT FROM TAXATION FOR FIVE YEARS.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 5.</lawnbr><fulltitle>An Act to amend article seven (7), section two (2), paragraph two (2) of the Constitution of this State by adding at the end of said paragraph another paragraph to be known as Paragraph Two A, to wit: Paragraph Two A. Any person, natural or artificial, a resident of this State who may after January 1st, 1924, build, equip, establish, or enlarge a plant for the manufacture or processing of cotton, wool, linen, silk, rubber, clay, wood, metal, metallic or non-metallic mineral, or combination of same, creamery or cheese plant; or for the production or development of electricity may, as to such building, enlargement or equipment, be exempt from all county, incorporated town or city ad valorem taxes for a period of time not exceeding five (5) years from the date of the beginning of the building, equipment, or enlargement of such plants. The legislature is herewith empowered to make provision for the operation of this paragraph by appropriate legislation, provided such exemption shall be approved by a majority of the electors voting in such county, incorporated town or city proposing said exemption.</fulltitle><p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the General Assembly of Georgia and it is hereby enacted by the authority of same, That article seven (7), section two (2), paragraph two (2)

<page id="GA1923.2.P65" no="GA1923.2.68" />

of the Constitution of the State of Georgia be and the same is hereby amended by adding at the end of said paragraph another paragraph to be known as Paragraph Two A, to wit: <sidenote>Art. 7, sec. 2, par. 2 of Constitution amended.</sidenote></p><p><blockquote><p>Paragraph Two A: Any person, natural or artificial, a resident of this State, who may after January 1st, 1924, build, equip, establish or enlarge a plant for the manufacture or processing of cotton, wool, linen, silk, rubber, clay, wood, metal, metallic or non-metallic mineral or combination of same, creamery or cheese plant; or for the production or development of electricity may, as to such building, enlargement, or equipment be exempt from all county, incorporated town or city ad valorem taxes for a period of time not exceeding five (5) years from the date of the beginning of the building, enlargement or equipment of such plants. The legislature is herewith empowered to make provisions for the operation of this paragraph by appropriate legislation, provided such exemptions shall be approved by a majority of the electors voting in such county, incorporated town or city proposing said exemption. <sidenote>Amending paragraph, Industries to be exempt.</sidenote> <sidenote>Period of exemption.</sidenote> <sidenote>Proviso as to approval of electors.</sidenote></p></blockquote></p><p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That when amendment shall be agreed to by a vote of two-thirds of the members elected to each of the two houses of the General Assembly, and the same has been entered on their journals with the ayes and nays taken thereon, the Governor shall cause said amendment to be published in one newspaper in each congressional district in this State for the period of two months next preceding the time of holding the next general election. <sidenote>Publication.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the above proposed amendment shall be submitted for ratification or rejection to the electors of this State at the next general election to be held after the publication as provided in section 2 of this Act, in the several election districts of this State at which election every person shall be qualified to vote who is entitled to vote for

<page id="GA1923.2.P66" no="GA1923.2.69" />

members of the General Assembly. All persons voting at said election in favor of adopting the proposed amendment to the constitution shall have written or printed on their ballots the words: <sidenote>Submitted to popular vote.</sidenote></p><p><blockquote><p>For amendment of constitution to encourage manufacturing and industrial enterprises in Georgia by exempting from city, incorporated towns and county, taxes for a period of time not exceeding five years, and all persons opposed to the adoption of said amendment shall have written or printed on their ballots Against amendment of constitution to encourage manufacturing and industrial enterprises in Georgia by exempting from city, incorporated towns and county, taxes for a period of time not exceeding five years. <sidenote>Wording of ballots.</sidenote></p></blockquote></p><p>Sec. 4. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That the Governor be and he is hereby authorized and directed to provide for the submission of the amendment proposed in this Act to a vote of the people as required by the constitution of this State in article 13, section 1, paragraph 1, and if ratified the Governor shall, when he ascertains such ratification from the Secretary of State to whom the returns shall be referred in the manner as in cases of elections for members of the General Assembly, to count and ascertain the result, issue his proclamation for one insertion in one of the daily papers of this State announcing such result and declaring the amendment ratified. <sidenote>Ratification and proclamation.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid, That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this Act be and the same are hereby repealed. <sidenote>Conflicting laws repealed.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 19, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1923V2N006" initial.page="69"><shorttitle>CIGARS AND CIGARETTES, TAX ON DEALERS IN; ACT AMENDED.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 6.</lawnbr><fulltitle>An Act to amend an Act, approved August 15, 1923, levying a tax upon dealers in cigarettes and cigars, providing

<page id="GA1923.2.P67" no="GA1923.2.70" />

for the collection of said tax, to require the use of stamps as evidence of the payment thereof; to prescribe penalties for the violation of said Act, and the counterfeiting of such stamps; to provide for the rules of evidence for the trial of persons charged with the violation of said Act; to appropriate the funds raised by such tax for the purpose of building and equipping new buildings for the State Tuberculosis Sanitarium at Alto, and for the purpose of paying the pensions now due and to become due under the Acts of August 5, 1919, August 18, 1919, and August 19, 1919, and for other purposes, so as to provide that the expenses of carrying out the provisions of said Act shall be defrayed out of the funds collected thereunder, and for other purposes.</fulltitle><p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the State of Georgia and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same, That the Act, approved August 15, 1923, entitled An Act to levy a tax upon dealers in cigarettes and cigars; to provide for the collection of such tax, to require the use of stamps as evidence of the payment thereof; to prescribe penalties for the violation of this Act and the counterfeiting of such stamps; to provide rules of evidence for the trial of persons charged with the violation of this Act; to appropriate the funds raised by such tax for the purpose of building and equipping new buildings for the State Tuberculosis Sanitarium at Alto, and for the purpose of paying pensions now due and to become due under the Acts of August 5, 1919, August 18, 1919, and August 19, 1919, and for other purposes, be and the same is hereby amended by adding the following provisions, to wit: <sidenote>Act of August 15, 1923, amended.</sidenote></p><p>The expenses of carrying out the provisions of this Act, including the necessary clerical help, cost of stamps and incidental expenses, shall be defrayed out of the funds collected hereunder, when said expenses are approved by the Governor, and the commissioner of revenue in his annual

<page id="GA1923.2.P68" no="GA1923.2.71" />

report to the General Assembly shall include a full and cempleted itemized statement of such expenses. <sidenote>Amending paragraph providing for necessary expenses.</sidenote></p><p>Amend further by striking from the second section of said Act the words each cigar, and substituting therefor the words each box, package, or other container of cigars, so that said section as amended will read as follows: <sidenote>Section 2 amended.</sidenote></p><p><blockquote><p>Section 2. Each dealer shall pay said tax to the Commissioner of Revenue of the State of Georgia, who shall thereupon furnish to such dealer stamps of such design and denominations as may be prescribed by said commissioner of revenue, and it shall be the duty of each dealer to affix to each package of cigarettes and each box, package, or other container of cigars a stamp, or stamps, furnished by said commissioner of revenue, evidencing the payment of the tax imposed by this Act, and to cancel such stamps before said cigarettes or cigars are offered for sale. <sidenote>Section 2, as amended, to read.</sidenote></p></blockquote></p><p>Sec. 2. Provided that wherever cigarettes are sold in cartons or other original containers said stamps may be affixed to each such carton or container and not to each package contained therein. <sidenote>Stamps affixed to carton or container.</sidenote></p><p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, That all laws or parts of laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed. <sidenote>Conflicting laws repealed.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 19, 1923.</approvaldate></law></part>

<page id="GA1923.2.P69" no="GA1923.2.73" type="INFERRED" />

<part><title>PART II.RESOLUTIONS<br set="CENTER" /></title>

<page id="GA1923.2.P70" no="GA1923.2.75" />

<contentslist><title>RESOLUTIONS.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p>Ordinary of Habersham County Furnished Georgia and Georgia Appeals Reports.</p><p>Congress Asked to Have Certain U. S. Navy Records Corrected.</p><p>General Assembly; Adjournment; Certain Members to Remain Four Days After.</p><p>Appropriation for Incidental Expenses of Extraordinary Session.</p></contentslist><law id="R1923V2N007" initial.page="75"><shorttitle>ORDINARY OF HABERSHAM COUNTY FURNISHED GEORGIA AND GEORGIA APPEALS REPORT.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 1.</lawnbr><lawtype>A RESOLUTION.</lawtype><p>Whereas, The County Courthouse of Habersham County was destroyed by fire on December 2, 1923, burning all the Georgia and Court of Appeals reports heretofore furnished the county by the State; <sidenote>Preamble.</sidenote></p><p>Resolved by the House, the Senate concurring, That the State Librarian be and is hereby directed to furnish the Ordinary of said county two full sets of Georgia and Court of Appeals reports. <sidenote>State Librarian to furnish Georgia and Georgia Appeals reports.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 11, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1923V2N008" initial.page="75"><shorttitle>CONGRESS ASKED TO HAVE CERTAIN U. S. NAVY RECORDS CORRECTED.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 2.</lawnbr><lawtype>A RESOLUTION.</lawtype><p>Whereas, Several hundred officers of the United States Navy, from the South, resigned from the service in 1861 to cast their fortunes with their native States, the resignations of the following one hundred and thirty-six were not accepted as follows: <sidenote>Preamble.</sidenote></p>

<page id="GA1923.2.P71" no="GA1923.2.76" />

<table><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">CAPTAINS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>French Forrest</td><td>Samuel Barron</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Franklin Buchanan</td><td>George N. Hollins</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">COMMANDERS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>William T. Muse</td><td>Thomas R. Roates</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Robert G. Robb</td><td>Chas. E. McIntosh</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Archibald B. Fairfax</td><td>Sidney Smith Lee</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Richard L. Page</td><td>Thomas L. Page</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Arthur Sinclair</td><td>Thomas T. Hunter</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John R. Tucker</td><td>Matthews F. Murray</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>William McBlair</td><td>John K. Mitchell</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">Chas. H. A. Kennedy</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">LIEUTENANTS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John Taylor Wood</td><td>J. Pembroke Jones</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Chas. M. Fauntleroy</td><td>Joseph N. Barney</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>George T. Sinclair</td><td>David P. McCorkle</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Robert B. Pegram</td><td>Charles W. Hays</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Washington Gwathmey</td><td>Alphonso Barbot</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>James H. Rochelle</td><td>Van R. Morgan</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>William Sharp</td><td>Hamilton H. Dalton</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Chas. F. M. Spottswood</td><td>George S. Shyrack</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Carter B. Poindexter</td><td>Joesph W. Alexander</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John S. Maury</td><td>Francis E. Sheppard</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John V. Bennett</td><td>John J. Guthrie</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Harry H. Lewis</td><td>William H. Ward</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John Wilkinson</td><td>Thomas K. Porter</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>William H. Parker</td><td>Wm. P. A. Campbell</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>William L. Powell</td><td>Henry K. Stevens</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John M. Brooke</td><td>B. P. Lovall</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Peter U. Murphey</td><td>Walter R. Butt</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Williams H. Muedaugh</td><td>Julian Meyers</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Edward L. Winder</td><td>Alex M. DeBree</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Charles C. Simms</td><td>Dulaney A. Forrest</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Robert D. Minor</td><td>William T. Glassell</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Oscar G. Johnston</td><td>Nicholas H. Van Zandt</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Hunter Davidson</td><td>John H. Parker</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Isaac N. Brown</td><td>James Iredell Waddell</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Silas Bent</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">SURGEONS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Lewis W. Minor</td><td>James F. Harrison</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Wm. B. Sinclair</td><td>Williams H. Page</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Randolph F. Mason</td><td>Daniel S. Green</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">Richard W. Jeffrey</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">PASS ASSISTANT SURGEONS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Charles W. Williams</td><td>H. W. M. Washington</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">J. W. B. Greenhow</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">ASSISTANT SURGEONS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Joseph Grafton</td><td>Robert J. Freeman</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Fred Van Bibber</td><td>Marcellus P. Christian</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Algeron S. Garnett</td><td>James E. Lindsey</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Bennett W. Green</td><td>James W. Herty</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John W. Sanford</td><td>O. S. Iglehart</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">PAYMASTERS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>George W. Clark</td><td>James E. Harwood</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John DeBree</td><td>Frelix Senac</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John Johnson</td><td>Thomas E. Ware</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Richard T. Allison</td><td>James A. Semple</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">MIDSHIPMEN.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Edward G. Read</td><td>James L. Taylor</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Thomas L. Dornin</td><td>George A. Borchert</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>James L. Hoole</td><td>Thomas L. Harrison</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Francis L. Hodge</td><td>Henry D. Claiborne</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Samuel W. Averett</td><td>Hilary Cenas</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">Arthur D. Wharton</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">CHIEF ENGINEERS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Michael Quinn</td><td>Thomas A. Jackson</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Wm. P. Williamson</td><td>James H. Warner</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">FIRST ASSISTANT ENGINEERS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Edward W. Manning</td><td>Virginius Freeman</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Henry A. Ramsey</td><td>George W. City</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">SECOND ASSISTANT ENGINEERS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John W. Tynan</td><td>Marshall P. Jordan</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">THIRD ASSISTANT ENGINEERS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Henry X. Wright</td><td>Edward L. Dick</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John T. Tucker</td><td>Benjamin Herring</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Chas. W. Jordan</td><td>Henry Fagan</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">BOATSWAIN.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">Chas. H. Hasker</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">GUNNERS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Chas. B. Oliver</td><td>John W. Lovett</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">MARINE CORPS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">Major Henry B. Tyler</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">Brevet Major G. H. Terrett</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">CAPTAINS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>John C. Rich</td><td>Robert Tansill</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Algernon S. Taylor</td><td>John D. Simms</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td align="CENTER" colspan="2">FIRST LIEUTENANTS.</td><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td /><td /></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Israel Green</td><td>J. R. F. Tatnall</td></tr><tr align="LEFT" valign="TOP"><td>Julius E. Meiere</td><td>Thomas S. Wilson</td></tr></table><p>and,</p><p>Whereas, The records of the Navy Department of the United States Navy at Washington record them as dismissed while the others are recorded as resigned, and</p><p>Whereas, The heroism of these men during the war between the States is an American heritage and may be the pride of every American citizen, and,</p><p>Whereas, The sons and grandsons of these dismissed sailors fought the battles of our country in the Spanish-American,

<page id="GA1923.2.P72" no="GA1923.2.79" />

and the late World War and are denied the privilege of joining patriotic organizations because of the stigma hanging over the memory of their brave ancestors, and,</p><p>Whereas, Admiral A. O. Wright, Commander of the Confederate Naval Veterans, has now pending a bill in the National Congress to remove this stigma;</p><p>Therefore be it resolved by the House of Representatives, the Senate concurring, That the representatives of the State of Georgia in the National Congress be requested to take the necessary steps at once to have the Navy Department at Washington accept these resignations, and thus remove the stigma of dismissal as the record now shows. <sidenote>Congress requested to have Navy Department accept certain resignations.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 19, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1923V2N009" initial.page="79"><shorttitle>GENERAL ASSEMBLY; ADJOURNMENT; CERTAIN MEMBERS TO REMAIN FOUR DAYS AFTER.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 3.</lawnbr><lawtype>A RESOLUTION.</lawtype><p>Resolved by the House, the Senate concurring, That the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House, the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House, be and they are hereby authorized to remain at the Capitol four days after the adjournment of the General Assembly for the purpose of affixing their signatures to bills and resolutions passed previous to said adjournment, and that they be allowed their per diem for said time, <sidenote>President and Secretary of Senate and Speaker and Clerk of House authorized to remain after adjournment.</sidenote></p><p>Resolved, further, That the chairman respectively of the enrollment and auditing committees of the Senate and House, together with the members of the Senate enrollment committee, and five members of the House enrollment committee, to be designated by the chairman thereof, and two members of the Senate auditing committee, and two members of the House auditing committee, to be designated by

<page id="GA1923.2.P73" no="GA1923.2.80" />

the chairman thereof, and the chairman of the Senate engrossing committee, and two members of the Senate engrossing committee, to be designated by the chairman thereof, and the chairman of the House engrossing committee, to be designated by the chairman thereof, be and they are hereby authorized to remain at the Capitol four days after the adjournment of the General Assembly for the purpose of bringing up the unfinished business of the session, and that they be allowed their per diem for said time, <sidenote>Chairmen and certain members of enrollment, auditing and engrossing committees authorized to remain after adjournment.</sidenote></p><p>Resolved, further, That the postmistress of the House be and she is hereby authorized to remain at the Capitol four days after the adjournment of the General Assembly for the purpose of distributing and forwarding members' mail, and that she be allowed her per diem for said time, <sidenote>Postmistress of House.</sidenote></p><p>Resolved, further, That two porters of the Senate, and three porters of the House be and they are hereby authorized to remain at the Capitol four days after the adjournment of the General Assembly and that they be allowed their per diem for said time. <sidenote>Porters.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 19, 1923.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1923V2N010" initial.page="80"><shorttitle>APPROPRIATION FOR INCIDENTAL EXPENSES OF EXTRAORDINARY SESSION.</shorttitle><lawnbr>No. 4.</lawnbr><lawtype>A RESOLUTION.</lawtype><p>Providing for the payment of the incidental expenses of the House and Senate for the extraordinary session of 1923.</p><p>Be it resolved by the House, the Senate concurring, That to pay the incidental expenses of the extraordinary session of the General Assembly of 1923, the sum of one hundred dollars for the House of Representatives and the sum of

<page id="GA1923.2.P74" no="GA1923.2.81" />

one hundred dollars for the Senate, or so much thereof respectively as may be needed, be and the same is hereby appropriated, to be paid on itemized accounts accompanied by the properly receipted vouchers for the same, and presented to the Governor by the clerk of the House of Representatives and secretary of Senate. <sidenote>$100 for the House, and $100 for the Senate for incidental expenses of extraordinary session.</sidenote></p><p>Resolved, further, That the sum of one hundred fifty dollars is hereby appropriated to pay the journal clerk of the House of Representatives and the journal clerk of the Senate, each the sum of seventy-five dollars for indexing the journal of the extra session of the General Assembly. <sidenote>$150 for indexing the Journals.</sidenote></p><approvaldate>Approved December 19, 1923.</approvaldate></law></part></body>

<page id="GA1923.2.P75" no="GA1923.2.83" type="INFERRED" />

<backmatter><index><title><b>INDEX</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>A<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>ACCOUNTS<br /></title><indexentry>All accounts of every department or agency of State government to be audited annually at least <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>ADJOURNMENT OF GENERAL ASSEMBLY<br /></title><indexentry>Certain members to remain four days after <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>AD VALOREM TAXES<br /></title><indexentry>Not subject to provisions of Act creating Department of Revenue <pagenbr>14</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Proposed Constitutional amendment exempting certain industries from taxation for five years <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>AMENDMENT<br /></title><indexentry>To Act of taxing retail dealers in cigars and cigarettes <pagenbr>69</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To Constitution; exempting certain industries from taxation for five years <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>AMENDMENT TO CONSTITUTION<br /></title><indexentry>Certain industries exempt from taxation for five years <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>APPROPRIATIONS<br /></title><indexentry>For incidental expenses of extraordinary session <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>AUDITS AND ACCOUNTS<br /></title><indexentry>Department of, created <pagenbr>7</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Auditor, State. See State Auditor</indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>AUTOMOBILE TAG TAXES<br /></title><indexentry>To be paid to the Secretary of State <pagenbr>16</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>B<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>BALLOTS.<br /></title><indexentry>See Election.</indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>BOND<br /></title><indexentry>Commissioner of Revenue to give; amount and conditions <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>State Auditor to give; amount and conditions <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1923.2.P76" no="GA1923.2.84" />

<indexdiv><title>BOARD OF EDUCATION<br /></title><indexentry>Duty of County Boards under Act creating State Text-Book Commission <pagenbr>19</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>State Board to act as State Text-Book Commission; duties under Act creating <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>C<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>CHAUFFEUR'S LICENSE TAXES<br /></title><indexentry>To be paid to Secretary of State <pagenbr>16</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>CIGARS AND CIGARETTES<br /></title><indexentry>Act taxing retail dealers in; amended to provide for expense of carrying out provisions <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Dealers in; books subject to audit by State; when <pagenbr>11</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Tax on dealers in; Act amended <pagenbr>69</pagenbr><pagenbr>71</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>COMMISSIONER OF REVENUE<br /></title><indexentry>Administrative officer of Department of Revenue <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Appointed by Governor <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Duty as to report of and payment of monies received <pagenbr>16</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Duty of as to delinquent and inheritance taxes <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Duty to direct prosecution against delinquents and to require tax collectors to issue executions <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Must collect delinquent license, special or occupation, automobile, chauffeurs' license, gasoline sales taxes, and stamp taxes on cigars and cigarettes <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Powers and duties <pagenbr>14</pagenbr><pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Report in detail; must submit to General Assembly annually <pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Salary and Bond <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>COMMISSION.<br /></title><indexentry>See State Text Book Commission.</indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>CONGRESS, UNITED STATES<br /></title><indexentry>Requested to have certain Navy Department records corrected <pagenbr>75</pagenbr><pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>CONSTITUTION.<br /></title><indexentry>See Amendment to Constitution.</indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1923.2.P77" no="GA1923.2.85" />

<indexdiv><title>D<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>DEPARTMENT OF AUDITS AND ACCOUNTS<br /></title><indexentry>Created <pagenbr>7</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE<br /></title><indexentry>Created <pagenbr>13</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>DELINQUENT TAXES<br /></title><indexentry>Duty of Commissioner of Revenue as to <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Penalty of twenty per cent for non-payment <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Special or occupation taxes delinquent, when <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>DEPOSITORIES, STATE,<br /></title><indexentry>See State Depositories.</indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>E<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>EDUCATION.<br /></title><indexentry>See Board of Education.</indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>ELECTION<br /></title><indexentry>To ratify proposed Constitutional amendment exempting certain industries from taxation for five years <pagenbr>68</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>EXEMPTIONS.<br /></title><indexentry>See Taxes and Taxation.</indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>EXTRAORDINARY SESSION OF GENERAL ASSEMBLY<br /></title><indexentry>Appropriation for incidental expenses of <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>F<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>FEMALE<br /></title><indexentry>Certain registered female voters relieved from poll tax <pagenbr>21</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>FORMS AND RECORDS<br /></title><indexentry>Duty of State Auditor to devise and install <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>FREE SCHOOL BOOKS<br /></title><indexentry>Furnished indigent pupils <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>G<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY<br /></title><indexentry>Certain members to remain four days after adjournment <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1923.2.P78" no="GA1923.2.86" />

<indexentry>Extraordinary session of; appropriation for incidental expenses <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>GENERAL TAX ACT<br /></title><indexentry><pagenbr>20</pagenbr><pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Abstract companies (Par. 5, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>23</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Adding machines (Par. 75, Sec.2) <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Ad valorem taxes (Par. 2, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>21</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>22</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Advertising agencies (Par. 6, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Amusement division (Par. 51, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Amusement parks (Par. 11, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Athletic clubs (Par. 12, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>25</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Auctioneers (Par. 13, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>35</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automatic sprinkler companies (Par. 36, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobiles (Par. 14, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>26</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobile accessories (Par. 16, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobile assemblying plants (Par. 18, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobiles for hire (Par. 21, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobile garages (Par. 20, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobile schools (Par. 17, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobile tires (Par. 16, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Automobile truck assembling plants (Par. 19, sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Awning or tent makers (Par. 22, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Ball and Racing Parks (Par. 27, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Banks (Sec. 11) <pagenbr>65</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Barber schools (Par. 23, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Barber shops (Par. 24, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Barber supplies (Par. 25, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Baths (Par. 26, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Beauty parlors (Par. 114, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>55</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bicycle dealers (Par. 78, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>44</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bill distributors (Par. 7, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Billiards, pool, etc. (Par. 28, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bond makers (bondsmen) (Par. 29, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Book agents (Par. 30, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bottlers (Par. 63, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bowling alleys (Par. 51, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>BrokersMerchandise, printing, railroad and theatre tickets (Pars. 32, 33, 35, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Building and loan associations (Sec. 12) <pagenbr>65</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Burglar alarm companies (Par. 36, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1923.2.P79" no="GA1923.2.87" />

<indexentry>Cafes and restaurants (Par. 98, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>51</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Carbolic acid gas (Par. 112, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>54</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Carbonated beverages (Par. 63, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Card writing stands (Par. 38, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Carpet cleaners (Par. 39, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Cash registers (Par. 73, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Cemetery companies (Par. 40, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Circuses (Par. 41, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Clipping Bureaus (Par. 43, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Coal and wood (Par. 44, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Collecting agencies (Par. 8, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commercial and mercantile agents (Par. 8, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commercial reporting agencies (Par. 109, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commission merchants (Par. 32, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Concerts, shows and exhibitions (Par. 45, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Conflicting laws repealed (Sec. 16) <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Construction companies (Par. 46, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>33</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Contractors (Par. 47, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>33</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Corporationsdomestic, foreign (Pars. 48 and 49 Sec. 2) <pagenbr>34</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>35</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Cotton warehouses (Par. 104, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Dance halls (Par. 50, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Date Act effective (Sec. 1) <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Defining clause (Sec. 15) <pagenbr>66</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Detective agencies (Par. 9, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Directories (Par. 53, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Dogs (Sec. 3) <pagenbr>55</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Dog and pony shows (Par. 54, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Dry cleaning (Par. 55, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Electrical agencies (Par. 56, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Emigrant agents (Par. 57, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Employment agencies (Par. 58, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Enforcement (Sec. 14) <pagenbr>66</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Equipment companies (Par. 3, Sec. 9) <pagenbr>63</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Film distributors (Par. 82, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Fire apparatus (Par. 36, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Fish dealers (Par. 107, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Gasoline or oil trucks (Par. 60, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>39</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Hotels (Par. 97, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>51</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Ice cream dealers (Par. 62, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>40</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1923.2.P80" no="GA1923.2.88" />

<indexentry>Insurance agents (Par. 61, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>39</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Insurance companies (Sec. 7) <pagenbr>58</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Itinerant practitioners (Par. 64, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Jitneys (Par. 21, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Junk dealers (Par. 65, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Laundries (Par. 72, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Legerdermain (Par. 66, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Legislative agents (Par. 71, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Lighting systems (Par. 67, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Lightning rods (Par. 68, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Livestock dealers (Par. 69, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Loan agents (Par. 70, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Machinery and equipment (Par. 80, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>44</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Manufacturing companies (Sec. 8) <pagenbr>60</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Merchandise brokers (Par. 32, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Merchandise warehouses (Par. 105, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Merry-go-rounds (Par. 81, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Monument dealers (Par. 90, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>48</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Motor Busses (Par. 21-A, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Motorcycle dealers (Par. 79, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>44</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Motion picture supplies (Par. 82, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Moving pictures and vaudeville performances (Par. 91, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>48</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Musical instruments (Par. 83, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>News dealers (Par. 84, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Officials (Par. 4, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>23</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Oysters, shrimp, etc. (Par. 107, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Packing houses (Par. 85, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>47</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Patent rights (Par. 108, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Pawn brokers (Par. 86, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>47</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Peddlers (Par. 88, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>47</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Phonographs, victrolas, etc. (Par. 83, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Photographers (Par. 87, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>47</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Pictures and picture frames (Par. 89, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>48</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Pistols, etc. (Par. 92, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Playing cards (Par. 37, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Poll tax (Par. 1, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>21</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Pressing clubs (Par. 55-A, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Printing brokers (Par. 33, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Professions (Par. 3, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>22</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1923.2.P81" no="GA1923.2.89" />

<indexentry>Railroad returns by whom (Sec. 10) <pagenbr>64</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Railroad returns to whom (Sec. 9) <pagenbr>62</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Real estate (Par. 34, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Real estate brokers (Par. 34, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Return by resident agents (Sec. 13) <pagenbr>66</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Safes and vaults (Par. 93, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Salary and wage buyers (Par. 111, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>54</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Sanatoriums (Par. 94, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Sewing machines (Sec. 4) <pagenbr>56</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shooting galleries (Par. 51, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Side shows (Par. 42, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Skating rinks (Par. 52, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Sleeping car companies (Par. 2, Sec. 9) <pagenbr>63</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Sleight of hand (Par. 66, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Slot machines (Par. 77, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Soda fountains (Par. 95, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Soft drink syrups (Par. 96, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Specifications and occupation taxes (Sec. 2) <pagenbr>21 et seq.</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Steamship companies (Par. 102, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Stevedores (Par. 110, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>54</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Stocks and bonds (Par. 31, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Stock and bond brokers (Par. 31, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Street carnivals (Par. 99, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Swimming pools (Par. 115, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>55</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Tank and pumping systems (Par. 100, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Taxes, how paid (Sec. 6) <pagenbr>57</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Taxes, how returned (Sec. 5) <pagenbr>57</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Teachers agencies (Par. 10, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Ticket brokersrailroad and theatre (Par. 35, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Toll bridges and ferries (Par. 113, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>55</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Trading stamps (Par. 101, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Traveling horse traders or gypsies (Par. 59, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Typewriters (Par. 76, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Undertakers (Par. 103, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Used carsautomobiles (Par. 15, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>26</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Water works (Par. 106, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Weighing or calculating machines (Par. 74, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1923.2.P82" no="GA1923.2.90" />

<indexentry>Wood and coal (Par. 44, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>GEORGIA REPORTS<br /></title><indexentry>Ordinary of Habersham County furnished Georgia and Georgia Appeals Reports <pagenbr>75</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>H<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>HABERSHAM COUNTY<br /></title><indexentry>Ordinary of, furnished Georgia and Georgia Appeals Reports <pagenbr>75</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>I<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>INHERITANCE TAXES<br /></title><indexentry>Duty of Commissioner of Revenue as to <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>L<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>LOCAL OPTION<br /></title><indexentry>Adopted as to furnishing of school books <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>M<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>MOTOR FUELS<br /></title><indexentry>Distributors of, books subject to audit by State, when <pagenbr>11</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>N<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>NAVAL RECORDS<br /></title><indexentry>Congress of United States requested to have certain resignations accepted <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>O<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>ORDINARIES.<br /></title><indexentry>See General Tax Act as to registrations with.</indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>P<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>PENALTY.<br /></title><indexentry>See Provisions of General Tax Act.</indexentry><indexentry>Delinquent tax payers subject to penalty of twenty per cent <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>When tax collectors lose rights to relieve delinquents of payment of <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1923.2.P83" no="GA1923.2.91" />

<indexdiv><title>PENSIONS<br /></title><indexentry>Pensions now due and to become due under Acts of August 1919, paid out of funds accruing from tax on cigars and cigarettes <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>POLL TAX<br /></title><indexentry>Provisions in General Tax Act (Par. 1, Sec. 2) <pagenbr>21</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>PUBLIC LAWS<br /></title><indexentry>Acts tabulated <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Relief of women voters <pagenbr>21</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>R<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>RELIEF OF DELINQUENTS<br /></title><indexentry>Time limit for <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>REPORTS AND EXAMINATIONS<br /></title><indexentry>Duty of State Auditor as to; and who may require <pagenbr>10</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>11</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>RESOLUTIONS<br /></title><indexentry>By General Assembly, tabulated <pagenbr>75</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>REVENUE<br /></title><indexentry>Department of, created <pagenbr>13</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>REVENUE, COMMISSIONER OF.<br /></title><indexentry>See Commissioner of Revenue.</indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>S<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>SALARIES.<br /></title><indexentry>See Acts creating Department of Audits, and Accounts and Department of Revenue.</indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>STAMPS<br /></title><indexentry>As evidence of payment of tax imposed on dealers in cigars and cigarettes <pagenbr>71</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>STATE AUDITOR<br /></title><indexentry>Appointed by Governor <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Devise and install correct forms and records; duty to <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Head of Department of Audits and Accounts <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Powers and duties <pagenbr>8</pagenbr><pagenbr>13</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1923.2.P84" no="GA1923.2.92" />

<indexentry>Recommendations to General Assembly; duty as to <pagenbr>13</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Salary and bond <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>STATE DEPOSITORIES<br /></title><indexentry>Special examination and reports by State Auditor <pagenbr>10</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>STATE TEXT-BOOK COMMISSION<br /></title><indexentry>Adoption of school books <pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Created <pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Duty of County Boards of Education under this Act <pagenbr>19</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Establishment of exchange rates or allowances <pagenbr>18</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Free school books; devising local option plan for, and fixing rental price where books are rented or loaned <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>School books furnished free to indigents <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>State Board of Education to act as <pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Supply of books and public notice <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>STATE TUBERCULOSIS SANITARIUM<br /></title><indexentry>New building and equipment paid for out of funds accruing from tax on cigars and cigarettes <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>T<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>TAX COLLECTORS<br /></title><indexentry>Must co-operate with Department of Revenue as to delinquents <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Taxes and Taxation. See Acts creating Department of Revenue and Department of Audits and Accounts.</indexentry><indexentry>Annual taxation ad valorem, poll, license and occupation taxes (General Tax Act) <pagenbr>22</pagenbr><pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Cigars and Cigarettes, tax on dealers in; Act amended <pagenbr>69</pagenbr><pagenbr>71</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Tax collectors must co-operate with Department of Revenue as to delinquents <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Proposed Constitutional amendments exempting certain industries from taxation for five years <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Text-Book Commission, State. See State Text-Book Commission.</indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1923.2.P85" no="GA1923.2.93" />

<indexdiv><title>U<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>UNFINISHED BUSINESS<br /></title><indexentry>Certain members of General Assembly to remain at Capitol four days after adjournment <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>UNITED STATES<br /></title><indexentry>Congress of, requested to have certain Navy Department records corrected <pagenbr>75</pagenbr><pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>W<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>WAR VETERANS.<br /></title><indexentry>See General Tax Act as to Certain Exemptions.</indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv></index></backmatter></document></galaw>
